2013年  当地球停止自转...
In 2013, when the earth's rotation came to a halt...
总统宣布所有的北美地区陷入灾荒
The president has declared all of north america a disaster area.
我呼吁所有的美国人团结起来...
I call on my fellow americans to come together...
...全世界呼吁一个可以逆转乾坤的人
...the world called on the one man who could make a difference.
当再次发生时  他将再次被召唤
When it happened again, the world called on him once more.
没人目睹三次以上
And no one saw it coming three more times!
如今
Now,
那个5次逆转乾坤的男人
The one man who made a difference five times before,
再次出手
Is about to make a difference again.
只不过这次  有所不同
Only this time, it's different.
谁没关冰箱门?
Who left the fridge open?
塔格・斯比德曼
Tugg Speedman.
全球融化
Global meltdown.
又来了
Here we go again.
Again.
还有什么要求吗
Will there be anything else?
是的  亲爱的  再来点豆子
Yes, my dear man. more beans.
哦  外婆
Granny!
别再放屁了
Please!
这个夏天  美国人最喜欢的肥胖家族回归
This summer, america's favorite obese family is back.
真恶心!
Gross!
-你不过是嫉妒我的苗条身材  -才不是
- you're just mad 'cause I'm skinny. - am not!
杰夫・珀特诺依
Jeff Portnoy.
杰夫・珀特诺依  放屁精续集
And Jeff Portnoy are fart two.
在一些国家
In some countries,
这是种表扬
It's considered a compliment.
这个夏天  释放吧
Letting loose this summer.
那个时代  与众不同是要被谴责的
In a time where to be different was to be condemned,
而被谴责就只有死路一条
And to be condemned was to die,
一个人选择了质问上天
One man chose to question his god.
在福克斯电影公司的聚光灯下
From fox searchlight,
5次奥斯卡奖的得主柯克・拉扎勒斯(也指麻风病)
Five-time academy award winner Kirk Lazarus
MTV电影奖最佳接吻奖得主  托比・麦格尔
And mtv movie award best kiss winner Tobey Maguire.
北京电影节垂涎哭猴奖得主
Winner of the beijing film festival's coveted crying monkey award,
恶魔的小巷(18世纪2个僧侣的爱情故事)
Satan's alley.
神父  我是个堕落的坏家伙
I've been a bad, bad boy, father.
在1969年的冬天
In the winter of 1969,
美国军队的一队精锐分子
An elite force of the u.s. army
被派到越南东南部执行一项顶级机密任务
Was sent on a top-secret assignment in southeast vietnam.
目标是从一个森严的东德人民军战俘营里
The objective, rescue sergeant Four Leaf Tayback
营救出福尔・立夫・泰柏克上士
From a heavily guarded nva prison camp.
这次任务被认为是自杀式行动
The mission was considered to be near suicide.
派出了10名人  只有4名生还
Of the 10 men sent, Four returned.
这4人当中  3个人就此次行动写了书
Of those Four, three wrote books about what happened.
这3本书中  出版了2本
Of those three, two were published.
这2本书中  只有1本得到了电影制作机会
Of those two, just one got a movie deal.
这就是关于想制作那部电影的人的故事
This is the story of the men who attempted to make that movie.
"威士忌老火蛇"请求着陆准备
Whiskey fire old snake requests an lz prep
降落在指定地点  完毕
At alpha-delta-two-four-eight-niner, over.
佛洛德  这是头机  注意  以右梯队着陆
Floyd, this is lead. right echelon approach from rp to lz, acknowledge.
佛洛德  "透视眼"空降部队  欢迎着陆
Floyd, wall-eye airborne. welcome aboard.
好的  领头机进去了  掩护她
All right, lead's going in. give her some cover.
5秒后发射  我再说一次  5秒后发射
Delivery on five. I repeat, delivery on five.
我是03号  我在你6点钟方向  别担心
This is zero-three. I'm on your six, don't worry.
"粉笔3号"开火了  射击
Chalk-three's taking fire. guns right, guns right.
快降下来
Lay that shit down!
快点
Come on!
快点  你这个肮脏的野蛮人
Come on, you damn dirty heathens!
"透视眼"  "透视眼"  这里是Z部的17号雷手
Wall-eye, wall-eye, this is boomer one-seven in the zee!
我需要些动作快点的美国佬  完毕
I need fast movers on my yankee smoke, copy?
雷手  "透视眼"回话  "蛇"24号
Boomer, this is wall-eye. I got two-alpha-four
-准备完毕  -哦天啊  日!
- snake and nape on the ready! - oh, jesus! holy shit!
日!
Holy shit!
拿起枪再上点火药  小子
Get on that horn and get some firepower, boy!
额滴老天爷哎
Jesus christ!
听着  你这个王八蛋
Listen, you cherry fuck,
赶紧给"蛇"打电话  再来点爆破  马上!
You call in that snake and nape and get us some boom-boom now!
要不是这么忙我就自己打了
I'd do it myself but I'm kind of goddamn busy!
请回答  雷手
I need an answer, boomer!
"透视眼"  "透视眼"
Wall-eye, wall-eye!
收到
I copy!
怎么回事?
What the fuck?
为了布鲁克林  混蛋
That's for brooklyn, motherfucker!
我想我能把它塞回去
I think I can put it back in!
这是维克多・查理日我的最后一个圣诞节
This is the last christmas I spend with Victor Charlie up my ass!
想要点吗  想要吗
Want some? get some!
你  胖子  我没看见福尔・立夫中士
Hey, yo, fats! I ain't seen Four Leaf!
别指望他会出来  那个混蛋屁股上有个幸运刺青
Don't count him out! that bastard's got luck tattooed to his ass!
莫唐  你TM赶紧挪动你那大屁股
Motown, get your detroit jukebox jheri curl ass
给我上这个鬼直升机
In this chickenshit chop-chop! asafp!
福尔・立夫还没有找到  中士
Four Leaf is still outside the perimeter, sarge!
想让我救那个混蛋吗  赶紧跑路吧(越南语)
Miss me with that cracker chump jive! we di di mau! we di di mau!
快点  卧倒  卧倒
Come on, get down, get down!
这是什么啊  我看见了什么啊
What am I looking at? what is this?
快点  快走  快走  起飞  快
Come on, let's get, let's go! come on, elevator up, up!
中士  那是福尔・立夫
Sarge. it's Four Leaf.
不要
No!
要活下来啊
Survive!
掩护我  你这个软蛋!
Cover me, you limp dick fuckups!
我看见你啦
Peek-a-boo! I see you!
坚持住  福尔・立夫!
Hold on, Four Leaf!
哦  该死
Oh, shit!
注意我右边
Watch my right!
快点  立夫  我们跑!
Come on, Leaf, let's boogie!
不要
No!
-胖子  -日!
- fats! - holy fuck!
看看你  伙计  还敢玩手榴弹
Look at you, man. playing with grenades.
林肯  我有点冷
I'm cold, Linc.
我感觉不到我的腿了
I can't feel my legs.
不过是块肉而已
Ain't nothing but a thang.
握住我的手
Hold my hands,
因为我有点话要...
'cause I got something to...
我有话要说
I got something to say.
哦  天啊
Oh, boy.
当我们离开这里时
When we get back to the world,
我要教你真正的变戏法
I'm gonna finally teach you how to juggle.
我这一生一事无成
I ain't never been worth a nothing in this life,
但有些事我要告诉你
But I want you to know something.
什么  伙计
What, man?
你是我的...
You are my...
你是我的兄弟
You are my brother.
你是我的兄弟  你是我的...
You are my brother. you are my... you are my...
我是你的兄弟
I am your brother.
抱歉  可以卡了么?
I'm sorry. could we cut?
-他说什么  -能停拍吗  达米安
- what's he saying? - Damien, can we cut?
-不  不  不  -好吧  你知道吗
- no. no, no, no, no, no... - all right, you know what?
直升机也到位了  大爆炸  2分钟呢
We got the jets coming in, big explosion, two minutes.
还在拍
Still rolling.
你知道吗  不  没在拍  能停拍吗
You know what? no, not still rolling. can we cut?
-已经在停了  -不  我们没有  滚
- we're cutting. - no, we're not. get out!
怎么啦  说真的  我屁股都疼了
Hey, what's going on? for real, my butt is hurting!
这个绳子要把我勒死了
This harness is riding up my crack!
-达米安  停拍没有  -不  不  还在拍
- Damien, are we cutting? - no! no! still rolling!
考克本先生  停拍没有
Mr. Cockburn! are we cutting, sir?
不  不  我没停拍  还在转呢
No! no. I'm not cutting! we're still rolling!
达米安  怎么啦  伙计
Damien, what's the dealy, dude?
我们还要要不要炸飞这些树了
Are we gonna blow this tree line or what?
塔克・塔克和金把蓝水球(也指无法射精)拿来了
Tuk Tuk and Kim got the blue balls here.
一声令下  我就会让他们射的
I'm gonna let them squirt if we're a go!
-继续  还在拍  -他能听见我说话吗  戴尔特
- play it through. still rolling! - Dieter, can he hear me?
这是C4  笨蛋  放下  我说要雷管
That's c-4, dipshit. put that back. I said a detonator.
我需要能说英语的人  该死
I need some dudes up here who speak american, god damn it!
他TM把这搞得一团糟
He's making a fucking sweater back here.
我正努力把这个丛林的老虎安抚下来呢
I'm trying to put tiger balm on this jungle's nuts.
哦  该死
Oh, shit!
阿帕・奇诺热线  怎么啦
Alpa Chino hotline. what's up? what's up, baby?
这TM怎么回事
What the fuck is going on here?
大家都给老子闭嘴
Everyone, please shut up.
直升机到位  我们只有一次机会了
The jets are coming in. we only have one chance at this!
数3下  宝贝  1  2  呼吸
On three, baby. one, two, breathe.
听着  帮我个忙  我不想在开拍前搞倒计时
Look, do me a favor. I don't want to do a countdown before I do the scene.
-不要倒计时?  -不要
- no countdown? - no countdown.
-好吧  -我们能不能直接说"开拍"?
- okay. - can we just do it off of "action"?
只说...随便你吧
Just... in your own time.
-很好  -我又不是卫星火箭
- good... - I'm not a rocket ship, okay?
-好吧  伙计  -开拍
- all right, dude. - and action!
只要你高兴就好  宝贝  靠  不要死
Whatever floats your boat, baby. fuck! don't die!
艾瑞卡  给我拿瓶维他命水来
Erika, get me a vitaminwater!
达米安  你知道么?  抱歉
You know what it is, Damien? I'm sorry.
我对他的表演没感觉
Not to get into his thing,
但如果我哭了  奥西里斯是不是也该哭啊?
But if I'm crying, should Osiris be crying, too
-不  大家都哭...  -要么停拍要么开哭?
- no, it's everyone cry... - we cutting or we crying?
-不  不要  还是哭吧  -只要下令就好了  哥们
- no, no, no, we're crying! - just call it, man!
-柯克  哭出来吧  塔格  哭出来吧  -多谢
- Kirk, you can cry. Tugg, you can cry. - thanks!
-大家都哭吧  -你知道吗?
- everybody cry... - you know what?
-看见他现在多焦躁了吧  -我明白
- you see how agitated he is now? - I know.
-喝点柠檬水吧  开工  -好的  还在拍
- let's make lemonade. let's go to work. - okay. still rolling!
我是猎鹰1号
This is falcon one.
我们接近山脊了  最多2英里
We have the ridge in sight, approximately two miles out
戴尔特  这些直升机就要到达山脊了
Dieter, these jets are about to crest this ridge line.
几乎有200磅的炸药
They got about 200 pounds of shit your pants.
我得知道我们是否准备好了
I need to know if we're ready to go.
-你是我的...你是我...  -我是你的...
- you're my... you're my... - I am your...
看见了吧  这就是我想的  达米安  我觉得台词不对
See, that's what I think it is, Damien. I think it's the line.
什么
Yeah?
我不知道福尔・立夫是否会这么说...福尔・立夫?
I don't know if Four Leaf would say that... Four Leaf?
当你的手都被炸开花了  你会哭吗
Were you crying when your hands blew up?
不  看啊  他没有  我是说  只是...
No. see, he didn't. yeah, I mean, just that's what...
那么我们现在又要重写剧本啦
So now we in re-writes, right?
-你去哪  -重写剧本
- where you going? - let's re-write it!
杰克森行动没有哭泣  你就是这意思
Action Jackson can't cry. that's what's going down.
你知道吗  柯克?  我可以拍这场戏的
You know what, Kirk? I'm ready to do the scene!
哪场?  这场是情感戏  可你动感情了吗?
What scene? the scene is about emotionality. where is it?
-现在该扔掉剧本了  -柯克...
- now it's time to flip the script! - Kirk...
等到中国新年时  我的人才会哭呢
Be here till chinese new year waiting for my man to cry.
他们来了
Here they come!
-柯克  不要  -别跟着我  你这个跟屁虫
- Kirk, no! - stop tailgating me, you pasty teabag!
我能去尿尿吗
Can I make pee-pee?
-那些飞机过来了  -我知道  该死
- the planes are inbound! - I know! oh, shit!
拿开水果...老天  他妈的!
Get the fruit... jesus! fuck! shit! cocksucking!
-发信号了  开始  开始  -热带风暴
- that's the signal! go, go, go, go, go! - tropic tits!
狗日的  该死
Goddamn shit-picking cock!
太美了
It's beautiful!
大自然也被吓得尿裤子了
Mother nature just pissed her pantsuit!
真NB啊  NB啊  靠
Hot! hot, hot, hot, hot! fuck!
-太爽了  -哦  妈妈咪呀
- sweet. - oh, mama!
让我下去
Let me down!
丛林中的失败之作
Bungle in the jungle.
"热带惊雷"在越南剧组的更多坏消息
More bad news from the vietnamese set of tropic thunder,
花了4百万美元烤焦了那块亚洲地盘
Where a $4 million explosion charred the asian location
但是连摄像机却都没开...
And the camera wasn't even rolling.
由性急的超级大亨莱斯・葛罗斯曼赞助
Financed by hotheaded mega-mogul Les Grossman,
传闻说这部电影的进度已经落后了一个月
The film is already rumored to be one month behind schedule
一共只拍摄了5天  什么原因呢?
Just five days into shooting. the reason?
责难都归咎在菜鸟导演达米安・考克本身上
Fingers are pointed at rookie director Damien Cockburn,
据知情人所说  他无法控制大牌的演员阵容
Who, insiders say, can't control a star-studded cast,
包括当红的"肥胖家族"演员杰夫・珀特诺依
Including flatulent star of the popular fatties franchise, Jeff Portnoy.
告诉你点小秘密  很多人都不尊重我
Let me tell you something. a lot of people are disrespecting me.
他们说那个电影都是屁  但那是关于家庭的
They say that the movie's just about farts. it's about family,
而且(去你妈的)...老子能做的你都做不到
And... you! you can't do what I do.
他最近一次被捕是由于吸毒和强行入室侵占财产
Fresh from his most recent arrest for heroin, glue and crack possession,
没有保险公司愿意接受珀特诺依的投保
Portnoy was almost uninsurable.
阿帕・奇诺这个嘻哈歌曲同样饱受争议
Also in the mix is Booty Sweat-hocking hip-hop hyphenate Alpa Chino.
我很激动  你知道我在说什么  拍摄"热带惊雷"
I'm so excited, you know what I'm saying, about doing tropic thunder.
喝"超级能量"吧
Hey, drink Booty Sweat, baby. drink Booty Sweat.
但剧组的重量级选手
But the real heavyweight on the set
是获得5次奥斯卡奖的  柯克・拉扎勒斯
Is five-time academy award winner Kirk Lazarus.
这个天才的澳大利亚人以现实坏小子形象
The brilliant australian known for his bad boy antics off-screen
和剧中他扮演的形象性格大相径庭而出名
Is famous for his total immersion into any role he portrays.
一个演员其实没什么不同
Well, being an actor is no different
作为一个演员其实和
橄榄球选手和建筑工人没什么不同
Than being a rugby player or a construction worker,
我的作用不过是
Save for the fact that my tools
燃起人们的情感之火
Are the mechanisms that trigger human emotion.
拉扎勒斯遭受着很大争议
Lazarus underwent a controversial
他进行了一个皮肤染色的手术
Pigmentation alteration procedure in order to play
为了要演这个黑人上士  林肯・奥西里斯
The platoon's african-american sergeant, Lincoln Osiris.
同样也和柯克一样努力保持银幕形象的是
Trying to hold his own onscreen with Kirk
动作演员塔格・斯比德曼
Is action juggernaut Tugg Speedman.
曾经作为世界级的明星
Once the highest Grossing star in the world,
最近他的电影人气有些下降
Lately his scorcher films have lost their heat.
近日  斯比德曼对泰拉敞开心扉
Recently, Speedman opened up to Tyra.
你没有真正的家人
You have no real family.
你是40岁阶层的叛逆者  你仍然幼稚并孤独
You're on the wrong side of 40. you're childless and alone.
一些和你亲近的人说过
Somebody close to you said,
"再失败一次  他就完蛋了"
"one more flop and it's over."
有人说和我很亲近?
Somebody said they were close to me?
今年对于塔格而言可不这么样
It's been a tough year for Tugg.
人气不高的友情戏剧"黑人剧院"
The disappointing buddy comedy chitlin' & the dude
由错误的尝试变成严重的笑话
Was followed by an ill-advised venture into serious dramatic territory.
"笨蛋杰克"讲述
Simple Jack,
一个可以和动物对话的弱智的农场工人的故事
The story of a mentally impaired farmhand who can talk to animals,
是个票房毒药
Was a box office disaster
很多批评言论说"是有史以来最糟的电影"
That many critics called, "one of the worst movies of all time."
我脑子不怎么好使
I ain't got a good brain.
我觉得你很聪明  杰克
I think you've got a fine brain, Jack.
你让我很开心
You make me happy.
但现在问题是  在号称历来投资最大的
But now the question is, can Speedman make audiences happy
这部战争片中
In what's being called the most expensive
-斯比德曼能让观众高兴吗  -瑞克・派克的电话
- war movie never made? - Rick Peck.
希望塔格这部电影能够成功
Wishing Tugg all the best on that one.
呼叫笨蛋塔格  我是派克  有时间和你经纪人聊一聊吗?
Rum-tum-tuggernauts, it's the Pecker. you got time for your agent?
-瑞克?  -嘿  哥们儿
- Rick? - hey, buddy,
猜我在看啥
Guess who I'm staring at right now.
-啥?  -我在"欣赏"你荣登
- what? - I'm looking at your ugly mug
《名利场》杂志封底的呆瓜"倩影"
On the back cover of vanity fair magazine,
抱着一只美到呆的靓女熊猫
Holding a cute, cuddly panda from cutesville.
太夸张了  很虐
It is insane, bro. you are a rock star.
对了  有没有收到我寄给你的礼物盒?
Hey, did you get the gift basket I sent?
这个是瑞克寄来的
From Rick.
收到了  很酷  谢了哈
Yeah. yeah. it's cool, man. thanks.
那可是个货真价实的卫星电话  兄弟
All right, that is a real satellite phone, bro.
可不要寄还给我
Do not re-gift.
你看到好莱坞那单工作了吗?
Hey. you see that access hollywood piece?
看到了  就像往小瞎子身上放枪
Yeah, I did. it was like pistol-whipping a blind kid.
我不会接这破工作的  塔格  你是超级巨星!
I mean, I'm not gonna sugarcoat it, Tugg. you are a huge star, all right?
但现在
But right now,
你就像操场上身单影孤的小毛孩
You're like that kid on the playground, you know,
就是身上有虱子所以没有朋友的那个
The one who has lice that none of the other kids want to play with?
-你是说?  -我是说要把你整理干净
- what do you mean? - I mean we gotta shave your head
拉回到儿童乐园的层面
And get you back on the monkey bars, right?
什么?
What?
对了  哭戏拍的怎么样?
How did the crying scene go?
非常糟糕  拉扎勒斯开始哭了
Horrible. Lazarus started crying.
并且伴随着剧本上没有提到的潺潺口水...
Then he starts drooling and dribbling, and it wasn't even in the script...
别说了
Stop right there!
你得加把劲了  拖拉船先生
You gotta buck up here, Tuggboat.
谁关心他的演技天分比你多?
Who cares how much more talented he may be than you?
他哭了  你就要哭的比他更猛
If he cries, you cry harder, man.
你小时候  你家的狗有没有
Didn't your dog have, like, leukemia or something
白血病之类的?  想想那个场景
When you were a kid? I mean, think of that.
胜负就揭晓了  他们数码录影机弄好了么?
Boom! end of story. they hook up the tivo yet?
-还没  -什么?
- no. - what?
他们有自己的数码有线电缆  没关系嘛
They have digital cable, but, I mean, it's okay.
什么没关系  拜托  大大滴有关系
No, no, no. come on, man. it's not okay.
你滴明白?  塔格!
It is not okay, Tugg!
你不需要解释为什么要数码录影机
And you don't need to explain to me why you need tivo
纯净水  干净床单  食物  睡觉的地方
Or clean water, clean sheets, food, shelter.
我都已经把这些争取到合同里了
I mean, I fought for that in your contract.
那收养的事又如何了?
How's the adoption thing coming, buddy?
不咋滴
Not too great.
好吧  至少你能自己挑
Well, at least you get to choose yours.
我已经死会了
I'm stuck with mine.
回去工作吧  天才士兵
Tell you what, get back to work, genius soldier.
派克去帮你完成数码录影机任务
The Pecker's on a tivo mission for the y-o-u.
用吃奶的力气挤出点眼泪来  亲爱的
Work on those tears, my man.
好吧  我会的
All right. yeah.
再对我说一遍
Say it for me one time.
你  让让让...让我快乐
- you make me happy. - make me happy.
-我爱你  伙计  -好吧  再见
- I love you, buddy. - all right, bye.
紧急会议?  什么意思?
Crisis meeting? what does that mean, exactly?
我们出了什么紧急情况吗?
I mean, are we in a crisis?
他是制片厂的老大
He's the head of the studio.
我们在一万英里之外
He's reaching out. we're 10,000 miles away.
他就想来个小会面
He just wants a little face-time.
是你说他称这个为紧急会议  所以我...
I know, it's just you said that he called it a crisis meeting. so...
他是莱斯・葛罗斯曼  最喜欢用这种夸张的形容词
It's Les Grossman. he throws these words around.
"危急关头"  "轰天爆炸"  "晕头转向"  "后院起火"这些
"crisis," "explosion," "not rolling," "fired."
就只是定语而已  毫无意义
These are just words.
以下保密  一辆摄影车被朱迪・戴区拉去做苦力了
Keep a secret? a camera truck in london just plowed into Judi Dench.
相信我  他麻烦大了
Trust me, he's got bigger problems.
他可能看得见我  但我可看不见他
Look, he may be able to see me, but I can't see him.
-闪开闪开  莱斯先生  -把你的大屁股抬开
- move! move! hello, Les! hello! - get your ass out of my...
-你的脚在我桌子上  -他看得见我们了吗?
- your feet were on my desk. - can he see us?
我就不明白为什么我们...
I don't know why we don't have...
给他一罐低脂可乐  莱斯  好用了!
Get him a diet coke. Les! it's working!
好了  停  你好  莱斯!
Yeah, whatever you're doing right there. hello, Les!
-你好  莱斯!  -好了
- hello, Les! - okay.
我们听得很清楚  莱斯
We got you loud and clear here, Les.
看见了  我看见你们了
I see you. I see you. I see you.
那个蠢脸是TM的达米安・考克本?
Which one of you fuckfaces is Damien Cockburn?
不才在下我  先生
That's me, sir.
真高兴见到你  来个小"会面"
It's good to finally meet you at last, get some face-time.
哪个是道具长  你?  你
And who here is the key grip? you? you.
你给我狠狠的揍那个导演的大饼脸
Hit that director in the face, really fucking hard.
得罪了
Sorry, man.
这都是你的错  你个英国来的傻×
This is your fault, you limey fuck!
你把我的钱当啥了?
You shit the money-bed, my friend.
嘿  莱斯  我能理解你很生气
Hey, Les, I understand if you're angry,
不过我这儿可伺候着一班太上皇呢!
But I am dealing with a bunch of prima donnas!
都是他  塔格・斯比德曼  他哭不出来!
Clowns! Tugg Speedman, he can't cry! he can't cry!
你知道怎么控制好演员?  他们一抱怨
You know how you handle an actor? they whine about anything,
把他们裤子脱了  抽一鞭子
You pull down their pants and you spank their ass.
-抽他们  莱斯  -什么?
- you spank that ass, Les. - what?
抽他们只会把他们搞成可怜虫
Spanking a child turns him into a little snot.
恐惧才会让人成长
Fear makes him a man.
我知道有个地方  能真正考验男人的价值
I know a place where a man's worth is measured
颈上的狗牌(军人颈上的金属牌)
In the ears hanging from his dog tags.
真正的东西
The real deep shit.
你要拍的逼真?
You wanna make this movie right?
你就得带着你的小娘娘腔们  去那儿体验一下
That's where you take your pansy-ass actors.
他又是谁?
Who is this guy?
莱斯  这是福尔・立夫
Les, that's Four Leaf.
福尔・立夫・泰柏克上士  是我写了那本书
Sergeant Four Leaf Tayback. I wrote the book.
你是美国的勇士  国家欠了你的
You're a great american. this nation owes you a huge debt.
不过现在请勿开尊口打扰我工作!
Now shut the fuck up and let me do my job!
-听着  考克本  -是
- look, Cockburn. - yes.
从现在开始  我的拳头离你的肛门就不远了
From now on, my fist is gonna be so far up your shithole
你一有了什么奇思妙想
That every time you have a thought,
就得问问我的结婚戒指答不答应
It's gonna have to tiptoe past my wedding ring.
管好你的演员  否则我就让你停拍
Take control of your actors, or I will shut you down.
我的低脂可乐呢!
Diet coke!
当羊群迷路时
When the herd loses its way,
牧羊人就会杀了带领它们迷路的领头羊
The shepherd must kill the bull that leads them astray.
-福尔・立夫?  -过来吧  别怕
- Four Leaf? - come on over. it's okay.
-坐下吧  -是
- sit down. - yes.
-你不喜欢旅馆的房间?  -席梦思让我做恶梦
- so, you don't like the hotel? - beds give me nightmares.
我猜对了  你用一艘俄亥俄的渔船
I'm guessing right about now you couldn't find a dixie coonskin
是找不到浣熊皮做的行军大铁锅的
With an ohio hooker holding your prick and showing you the way.
什么?
What?
我的故事交到了你这个英国佬的手上
I put my story in your limp brit hands,
你可不能让我失望
And you are not going to fail me.
你以为我在会议上那是虚张声势?
You think I was just blowing my own bagpipe in that meeting?
你必须带着那帮孩子到那儿去!
You must put those boys in the shit.
什么?  我没明白
What? I don't understand.
-你还想搞好你的电影吗?  -当然了
- you wanna make your movie or not? - yes, I do.
那好  你就带着你那些小摄像机
All right, you get some of those little video type cameras.
带到丛林那儿  放置在不同的角落
We take them out there, and we put them in the trees in different angles.
然后你把所有的烟幕弹  冲锋枪  炸药  雷管
Then you give me and that pyromaniac Cody
都给我和负责爆破的科迪
All the smoke bombs, charges, explosives, detonators you got.
然后带那些演员去那儿
Then we take those boys up there,
我和科迪  会炸了那个丛林
Me and Cody, we could light up that fucking jungle,
那些小娘娘腔演员会吓得屁滚尿流
So those lily-dick actors would be shitting their pants
吓得尖声叫妈
And screaming for their mammies.
他们宁愿被卷在裹尸布里面如果可以回家
They'd be begging for a body bag if it means a ride home.
我可以这么干
I could do it.
我可以把一切弄成游击式的  风沙  泥土
I could shoot the whole thing guerrilla style. gritty, dirty.
把他们和那些奶妈似的的助手保姆们隔离开
Get them away from their helpers and ass-licking assistants.
让他们处在真实的战争环境中
Put them in the real shit.
-真实环境  -要从他们的眼中看到真正的恐惧!
- real shit. - with real fear in their eyes!
真正的恐惧  真实的感情!  福尔・立夫  太好了!
Real fear, real emotion! yes, Four Leaf, yes!
-就这么干  -对  就这么干!
- yes! yes! - yes! yes!
让他们身处绝境
Take them off the fucking grid!
你们不再是电影演员
You are no longer actors in a movie!
你们就是直升机里的五个军人
You are five men in a helicopter!
还有三个陌生人:我们
With three other men!
那我们什么时候能回去?
How long are we gonna be gone, anyways?
我的大部分维他命都留在旅馆里了
'cause I left most of my vitamins back at the hotel.
-省口气吧  小蛆儿  -没错  小蛆儿
- save your breath, maggots! - that's right, maggots!
下去!  都下去!
Go, go, go! get out of the chopper!
快  小蛆儿们  快走  步兵们  动起来
Move it, maggots, move! move, grunts, move your ass!
快出去!  你们这帮寄生虫
Get out, you wriggly worms!
-太高了!  -滚
- it's up too high! - move, move, move!
我们地狱见
See you in hell!
这什么狗屁情况  我最少得打个电话告诉我助手吧
This is bullshit! I gotta at least call my fucking assistant.
日!  伙计你TMD干嘛!
Fucking! jesus! dude!
你在一队维多利亚十字军的敌人面前
You're sitting on a nest of hostile enemy v.c.
祝贺你  死胖子  你把我们都害死了
Congratulations, fats. you just got us all killed.
谁还想泄漏我们的行踪给那群傻瓜助手的?
Anybody else care to give away our position to Charlie?
把手机都交出来!
Cell phones!
达米安  这是TM怎么回事?
What the hell, Damien?
69年可没有手机  我从头到脚标准配备
Weren't no cell phones in '69, man. I'm head-to-toe legitimate.
同志们  我这儿有好消息和坏消息
Gentlemen, I've got good news and bad news.
坏消息是  制片方想放弃我们
The studio wants to shut us down. that's the bad news.
好消息是
And the good news.
如果你们想拯救这部电影  你们就成为一个连队
If you wanna save this movie, you will become a unit.
你们的目标是跨越当库河到北边
Your objective is to head north to the D'ang Kwook River
解放战俘营
And liberate the pow camp,
也就是福尔・立夫会让自己被抓到的地方
At which point Four Leaf will get himself captured,
你们要去营救他
At which point you will rescue him,
然后直升机会送你们回家
At which point we will chopper you home!
福尔・立夫  既然你是上士
Four Leaf, since you're the staff sergeant,
这是地图  这是场景名单
There's the map, this is the scene list.
你们可以搞定吗?
Think you can handle it?
我们在这整个死亡之谷布满了隐藏摄像机
We have rigged this entire valley of death with hidden cameras.
我也会在镜头外亲自拍摄
And I will be shooting as well, from unseen vantage points,
所以每一个辉煌的时刻都会被电影记录在册
So that every glorious moment is captured on film.
相信我  伙计们  这会是光彩夺目的一章
And believe me, gentlemen, it will be glorious.
如果看上去越逼真  赢来的机会不言而喻
If it looks real, chances are it probably is.
你们想成为演员
You wanted to be actors.
你们想披起别人的皮演好戏
You wanted to occupy the skin of another human being.
准备好披上被吓倒的美国步兵连的画皮
Well, get ready to occupy the skin of a terrified u.s. infantry grunt,
死亡无处不在  撒旦近在咫尺
Surrounded by death, crawling up satan's bottom.
会有埋伏  敌军开火  你们自己的各种障碍
There'll be ambushes, enemy fire, your own little personal slice of 'nam.
这个步话机只能和直升机通信
This radio goes to the chopper and the chopper only.
直升机就是上帝  而我是上帝之子  耶和华
The chopper is god, and I am jesus christ, his son.
你们是我挑选的信徒
You are my chosen disciples.
我们没有完成目标之前  谁都回不了家
And no one gets to go home till we get the shots.
换上你们的战争画皮  伙计们
Put on your war faces, gentlemen.
我们一起创造这前所未有精彩绝伦的战争电影
Now, let's go and make the greatest war movie ever!
-好的  -没错!
- yeah! - all right!
不错啊  考克本
Not bad, Cockburn!
装的挺像哈
Not bad.
不管你在哪儿
Wherever you are!
不管他在哪儿?  看来他到处都是啊
Wherever he is? looks like he's all over the place.
这肯定是个老旧的法式地雷
Must be an old french mine.
是印度和中国殖民的残留  这个丛林里肯定到处都是
It's a remnant from colonial indo-china. this jungle must be full of them.
你们还不明白吗?  他在玩心理战
Don't you get it? he's messing with our heads.
这就是为什么他一直在扮神
That's what all that playing god stuff was about.
他在试着让我们演好点  拯救这部电影
He's trying to get us to act good, save the movie.
他不是在扮神  他是被神裁决了
He ain't playing god. he's being judged by him.
这就是我们的目标  完成任务
That's our objective. complete the mission.
无疑冒犯  柯克  我知道你是这儿最有名的
No offense, Kirk, I know you're the big fancy actor here,
不过我可比你拍了更多的效果电影
But I've done a lot more effects-driven event films than you. okay?
我可以认出
And I think I can spot
死人头的道具
A prop head when I see one.
这就是玉米糖浆而已  玉米糖浆和乳胶
It's corn syrup, guys. corn syrup and latex.
温暖的  带着血液味道的玉米糖浆
Warm, blood-flavored corn syrup.
烟熏火燎镜像万千伙计们  欢迎来到电影工厂
Smoke and mirrors, guys. welcome to the movie factory.
书上的老把戏
Oldest trick in the book.
他吞下去了
He getting down now.
看我
Whoa, look at me!
你们要完成目标
You're going to get the shots,
我要监督你们  因为我是导演
And I'm going to make sure because I'm the director.
我来自伦敦  我导演戏剧
I'm from london. I direct plays.
嘿  达米安  我们已经换上军人画皮了
Hey, Damien! we got our war faces on!
看啊  我是大卫・贝克汉姆
Look, I'm dave beckham.
我们今天的任务是把他们"炸"翻了  对吧?
So, we gotta light these boys up today, huh?
让这些年轻人长长见识
Blow some sense into these young men.
我不想搞得很尴尬
Hey, I don't want to come off as weird or anything,
但我或许可以算是你的粉丝团团长了
But I might be your biggest fan. yeah.
《热带惊雷》  我随身携带
Tropic thunder. kind of like my catcher in the rye.
虽然我本身从未在军队呆过
Yeah, I've never been in the military, per se,
不过我在工作中丢了一只手指
But I have lost an appendage in the line of duty.
驾驶首架摄影用马车的时候
Driving miss daisy, first studio gig.
这个真酷  是什么?
It's a pretty cool sidearm you got there. what is it?
我不知道它是什么
I don't know what it's called.
我只知道当它取走人的性命时的声音
I just know the sound it makes when it takes a man's life.
好吧
Okay.
达米安  我们等着你发号施令呢
Damien, we're go for explosion.
你说可以了我们就开炸
Ready to kick the tires and light the fires on your say-so.
达米安  我们等着你呢
Damien, we're go for explosion.
收到没?
Do you copy?
我扣扳机的手指都发痒了  想闹个翻天覆地呢
I got an itchy trigger finger here, and I'm ready to blow some shit up.
现在可以了么?  我们可以开始了吗?
All right, you happy now? can we do the scene?
还是你们在等一个正式邀请?  我们上吧
Or do you need a formal invitation? come on, let's go!
"第12场景  林中空地  埋伏"
"scene 12, exterior, jungle clearing, day, ambush.
"福尔・立夫会用信号通知你们行动"
"four leaf notices movement in the brush.
"一堆游击队员会在林木线处移动"
"a dozen guerrilla fighters can be seen moving in the tree line.
"随地有地雷会爆炸"  还有你
"somewhere a mine explodes." and you.
"我有点不祥的预感"
"i got a bad feeling on this one."
-没错  -不  这是你的台词
- yeah. - no, that's your line.
-我有点...现在?  -是的  不过演的害怕些
- I got... now? - yeah, but scared. like, scared.
-"我有点不祥的预感"  -再来一次?
- "i got a bad feeling on this one." - dude, wait, like how?
"我有点不祥的预感"
"i got a bad feeling on this one."
-好吧  -开拍  快  快
- okay. - action. go, come on.
我有点不祥的预感  胖子
I got a bad feeling on this one there, fats.
我们可不会在这儿出事
Our asses don't get fragged in this bullshit valley,
回去第一件事  我要花2块钱
First thing I'm doing is paying my 2 bucks
我可以看布鲁克林咬一咬风骚妈妈桑
So I can watch brooklyn bust his cherry
手下"乖女儿"的小樱桃
On a sweet little mama-san's dinky dau poontang.
布鲁克林死了也弄不到小妞
Shit, brooklyn be bagged and tagged before he get any cooch.
他死了  估计死在哪个带把的手上了
He die, he probably die a coochless motherfucker.
闭嘴  莫唐
Zip it, motown.
兄弟  我口真渴
Man, I'm thirsty.
可以喝我在越南买的"超级能量"
Might as well have some of this booty sweat I got back in danang.
你们这群蠢货  这个白痴死了
Yo, asshole! this motherfucker's dead!
这不是什么安吉尔的街头魔术
Ain't no criss angel mindfreak,
或者大卫・布莱恩的机关魔术
David blaine trapdoor horseshit jumping off here!
你是要跟我们一起  还是想再搞砸拍摄
Hey! you wanna get on the train here, or do you wanna ruin another take?
压根就没拍摄  没他妈的电影
There ain't no goddamn takes, ain't no goddamn motion picture!
-你确定?  -没错
- you sure? - yeah.
-对么?  -肯定  老兄
- yeah? - for certain, man.
那怎么你还这么入戏?
Then why are you still in character?
我明白  但不必告诉你
I know, but I don't have to tell you.
你不明白
You don't know.
老兄  我要一直入戏到DVD出完评论为止
Man, I don't drop character till I done a dvd commentary.
现在高兴了?  我们的走位都没好
You happy now? we're out of position for the effects!
趴下  傻瓜
Get down, fool!
没人读剧本么?  这是伏击
Didn't anyone read the script? this is the ambush!
-感觉太真实了  -没错  我们好好利用下
- this feels pretty real! - exactly! let's use it.
吃枪子儿吧
Eat lead!
下面那帮人打得跟真的似的
They're busting caps like a motherfucker down there.
乱成一锅粥了  我提议后援他们
This is fubar. I say we juice them.
-你觉得怎样?  -后援
- what do you think? - juice them.
干你的  查理
Fuck you, Charlie!
让你爽歪歪
Big-ass titties!
你看看
Look at that, huh?
停止拍摄
And cut!
够做宣传片用了
That's the trailer right there.
-现在干什么  -耶
- what do we do now? - yeah.
向北  他说向北走
North. man said to head north.
-看到我狂射了么  -就那样  很好
- did you see me shooting? - that's how we do. good work, baby.
我还真信了
I believed it.
当库河
D'ang kwook river.
我打赌一路上还会有更多
I'm betting he's got more of these battles
和越共佬打斗的场面
And viet congs rigged for us along the way.
奥西里斯上士  让你的人上弹拉好保险
Sergeant Osiris, get your men. load and lock.
真的  宝贝  我说真的
Real, baby, I'm real.
出发  前面的仗还多着呢
Let's go! we got a lot of klicks to cover!
男士们  动起来  排成一队
Hump it up, gentlemen! single formation.
别游手好闲了
Don't dawdle now!
D棒  D棒  这是布丁脸  情况如何了
D-rod, d-rod, this is puddingface. how are we coming on that hotplate?
出事了  我认为我们得去看看
Something's up. I think we better drag ass back there.
确认下达米安还没忘怎么用对话器
Make sure Damien ain't forgot how to use his talkbox again.
宝儿  来一点就好
Yeah, baby, come on. just a little taste.
-杰夫  干嘛呢?  -我日  没什么
- what are you doing, Jeff? - fucking... nothing, man!
-吃软糖呢  -哇  我也喜欢  能给点给我...
- I'm eating jellybeans. - wow, I love jellybeans. can I please...
不行  门儿都没有
No, you can't have any fucking jellybeans.
都是我的
They're mine.
你觉得你是这儿唯一一个没软糖
You think you're the only one who gets sick
就要生病的人?
When he doesn't have his jellybeans?
原则问题  日
Boundaries, man. fuck.
嘿  之前我并不是找你茬
Hey. I didn't mean to show you up back there.
只是我觉得我们得
It's just, I feel like we really need
给其他人树立榜样
To set the example for the other guys
会挺艰难
It's gonna be tough,
但我认为达米安一定能拍到很赞的画面
But I think Damien's gonna get some great shit out of us.
多希望当时拍杰克的时也有个这样的导演
Just wish I had a director like this on Jack.
拍什么杰克?  你在说什么
On Jack. what? Jack? what you talking about?
-笨蛋杰克  -哦  对
- simple Jack. - oh, yeah.
笨蛋杰克  你全力以赴的吧
Simple Jack, yeah. you went all out on that one, huh?
真的  打全垒打了  对吧
You did. really swung for the fences, huh?
谢谢  谢了
Thank you. thanks. yeah.
没错  是次很深刻的经历
Yeah, it was an intense experience, you know.
下了很多功夫
I just did the work.
观看一群弱智的人  花时间观察他们
Watched a lot of retarded people. spent time with them. observed them.
观看他们做的弱智事情
Watched all the retarded stuff they did.
而我总是觉得对它的观察
Then again, I always found mere observation
是很细小基础的东西
In and of itself is a tad rudimentary.
有时  我们得更深入的找寻内心情感
Sometimes, we gotta dig deeper to mine the true emotional pay dirt.
从而才能分析痛苦的来源  才能与之共存
Thus, we can diagram the source of the pain and then live it, you know.
对  对  与之共存  没错
Yeah, yeah, live it. yeah, exactly.
你知道么  当我在拍杰克的时候
You know, there were times when I was doing Jack
有时我真感觉自己弱智
That I actually felt retarded,
-真正的弱智  -妈的
- like really retarded. - damn.
我要以奇怪的方式释放自己
In a weird way, I had to sort of just free myself up
安慰自己愚蠢智障没什么
To believe that it was okay to be stupid or dumb.
-当个低能儿  -对
- to be a moron. - yeah.
-低能的  -对  当个低能儿
- to be moronical. - exactly, to be a moron.
-痴呆儿  -对
- an imbecile. - yeah.
-像是有史以来最傻的白痴
Like the dumbest motherfucker that ever lived.
当我扮演这个角色的时候
When I was playing the character.
-当你进入这个角色时  -对  完全进入杰克
- when you was the character. - yeah, as Jack, definitely.
杰克  傻X的杰克
Jack, stupid ass Jack.
当结束拍摄使  我在想
By the end of the whole thing, I was like,
等一下  我入戏太深了
"wait a minute, I flushed so much out,
我该怎么重新回到生活
How am I gonna jumpstart it up again?
-感觉很...对吧  -对
- it's just like... right? - yeah.
你在浴缸里放屁  笑掉大牙
You was farting in bathtubs and laughing your ass off.
对  我是说  这太疯狂了
Yeah. I mean, it was really quite a... it was crazy.
兄弟  是高科技  一种艺术形式
It's like working with mercury. it's high science, man. it's an art form.
-对  -你是个艺术家
- yeah. - you an artist.
-这不就是我们干的么  -对
- that's what we do, right? yeah. - yeah.
向做到这样脱帽敬礼
Hats off for going there,
特别是知道奥斯卡是怎么回事的人
Especially knowing how the academy is about that shit.
-什么东西  -你当真不知道?
- about what? - you're serious? you don't know?
是人都知道不能变成彻底的弱智
Everybody knows you never go full retard.
-什么意思  -你听听看
- what do you mean? - check it out.
达斯汀・霍夫曼主演雨人  看着弱智  表演弱智  但他不弱智
Dustin hoffman, rain man, looked retarded, act retarded, not retarded.
数牙签  纸牌作弊  自闭  但不弱智
Count toothpicks, cheat at cards. autistic, sure. not retarded.
再来看汤姆・汉克斯  主演了阿甘正传
Then you got tom hanks, forrest gump.
迟钝没错  也许有点弱智  腿上装着矫正器
Slow, yes, retarded, maybe, braces on his legs.
但他征服了尼克松总统  赢了乒乓球比赛
But he charmed the pants off nixon, and he won a ping-pong competition.
那当然不弱智
That ain't retarded.
彼得・塞勒斯  也一样  幼稚但不弱智
Peter sellers, being there. infantile, yes. retarded, no.
而你则从头到尾彻底智障了
You went full retard, man.
千万别彻底智障
Never go full retard.
你不信?  去问演《我是山姆》的西恩・潘
You don't buy that? ask sean penn, 2001, I am sam.
想起没?  彻底智障  一无所有
Remember? went full retard? went home empty-handed.
干得好  特德  你杀了导演
Good job, Turd. you killed the director.
不可能  老兄
No, that's impossible, man.
我为这片装的炸弹  而他在这里
I rigged the whole tree line, and this is here.
-他肯定走错步了  -走错步了?
- he must have missed his mark. - missed his mark?
对  不关我的事
Yeah, this isn't me.
行了  把这个混蛋包起来送回酒店
Come on, let's bag and tag the bastard and get back to the hotel.
-你可死定了  傻瓜  -是我们死定了
- you're in a world of hurt, dumbo! - we're in a world of hurt!
-这是你的问题  -不止是我的问题
- you're in trouble. - this isn't just on me!
-我们是一起的  -胡说
- we're in a... we're together on this. - bullshit.
你打算逃跑  离开
You're just gonna run away. you're gonna leave.
你不是说"永不抛弃同伴"么?
What happened to, "no man left behind," okay?
等等  等等  听我说
Just wait, just wait! listen! listen, okay?
-我不想听  -我老实给你说
- I don't wanna hear it. - let me just be real with you, all right?
我差点在辣妈辣妹中弄瞎杰米・李・柯蒂
I almost blinded Jamie Lee Curtis on freaky friday, okay?
这会毁了我
This shit will fucking ruin me!
-你放开我  你可悲  -我不可悲
- just get off me! you're pathetic. - no, I'm not.
-放开我  -不准回去
- get off me! - you are not going back!
-我日  -等下
- what the fuck? - now wait a minute.
我他妈讨厌电影
I fucking hate movies.
狗屎  我不要拍这狗屎的电影
This is bullshit. I don't wanna be in this shitty movie.
别  那是我的软糖
No! that's my jellybeans! no!
伙计  抓住那只蝙蝠  我日
Kid, grab the bat! please! shit!
-兄弟  我有吃的  -去死吧  在那里
- yo, man, I got a bust-a-nut. - you go to hell! there he is.
我日  跑哪儿去了
God damn it! okay. where'd he go?
你个小混蛋  老子日掉你的翅膀
You little piece of shit! I'm gonna fucking rip your wings off!
杉搭奇  别动  别慌张
Sanducci. hold up, man, keep it on the down-low.
我不是真要尿尿  只是想和你谈谈
I don't really gotta piss. I'm trying to talk at you, man.
诱饵  我要诱饵
Bait, I need bait.
你进过海军新兵训练营地对吧  能看地图么
You went to boot camp, right? you can read a map?
差不多吧
Yeah, I think so.
我知道斯比德曼说服我们都留下来
I know Speedman got everyone convinced we out here
像拍个决战猩球放到Youtube上面之类的鬼话  我不信
Making planet of the apes on youtube or some shit, but I don't buy it.
你想踩到真的地雷上  你想送死?
You wanna step on a real landmine? you wanna die?
你想被人射死?
You wanna get shot by a real motherfucker?
-朝前看  -不  当然不想
- keep looking ahead, man. - no, of course not.
如果我把地图交给你  靠得住你么
If I can put that map in your hands, can I count you in?
-可以  我想可以  -好  我尿完了
- well, yeah, I guess you can. - dynamite. I'm out.
闻起来像博洛尼亚香肠
That smelled just like bologna for some reason.
有他妈人来帮我抓这该死的东西么
Is anyone gonna fucking help me get this fucking thing?
他们怎么白天都出来了
Why are they even out in the daytime?
我得跟你说实话  兄弟  我不尿就是跟你谈谈
I'm gonna level with you, bro. I don't need to pee. I need to talk to you.
拉扎勒斯要把这电影搅黄
Lazarus is gonna torpedo the movie.
他有点偏离现在这个角色了
He's way out on a limb with this character,
我觉得他临阵畏缩
And I think he's getting cold feet.
-我需要你站在我这边凯尔  -我叫凯文
- I need you on my side, Kyle. - it's Kevin.
很好  靠得住你么
Good. can I count on you?
如果可以  我能看看那地图
Yeah. if you want I could give the map a look-see.
-地图我来弄  -好的
- I'll handle the map. - okay.
我们按计划  就能完成电影拍摄
You stick with the program, we get this movie in the can,
我觉得你能获得年轻人选择奖
I'm thinking there could be a teen choice award in it for you.
你有潜质  他们会捧你的
You have that potential. they'll slime you, the whole deal.
-好  那太棒了  -好的
- yeah, that's wicked. - good.
这儿  现在死了吧
There it is! yeah, now you're dead!
你这该死的
You o.d.'d!
杰夫  等等
Hold up now, Jeff.
你干什么  杰夫  只是只蝙蝠
What the hell, Jeff? that's a bat, man!
我没软糖了
I don't have any more jellybeans.
在那里降落
You land there!
哇  悄悄这片废墟
Wow. look at these ruins.
-我们在哪儿  -当库河
- where the hell are we? - D'ang Kwook River.
是么  你怎么知道  你确定?
That so? how do you know that? how you sure?
只有走了才知道  老兄  出发
Only one way to find out, dude. let's go.
我感觉不对  真的  皮肤痛
Yeah. I'm not feeling so good right now. seriously, my skin hurts!
别在上面了  到水下来  娘们
Enough from the peanut gallery! into the water, ladies!
别  让我看看地图
No, man. let me take a look at that map right quick.
怎么大家都对地图着迷
Why is everybody all obsessed with the map?
因为我们厌倦了当你的跟班
'cause we're tired of being your trail donkeys!
演得跟你是个真人GPS似的
Acting like you some one-man gps!
操娘的  我们迷路了  彻底迷路了
God damn it! we lost! we fucking super lost, man!
麦克拉斯基告诉他  现在几点了
Tell him, Mcclusky. tell him what time it is.
真不敢相信你们这些人
I don't believe you people.
你说"你们这些人"是什么意思
What do you mean "you people"?
What do you mean, "you people"?
我觉得塔格的意思是...
I think what Tugg means is...
不  看着他的眼睛
No, look at his eyes, man.
...你们这些人  你们这些演员...
...you people, you actors. you people...
-看着眼珠子  -白种眼珠子
- look at them beady, white devil eyes
我要回到酒店  说真的
I gotta get back to the hotel, for real!
-停下来  -安静
- hell, no! - silence!
冷静点  好么  冷静下来
Chill! all right? just chill it.
我们去打越共佬佬
Now, let's go get those viet congs.
-"越共佬"  -什么
- "viet cong"! - what?
是"越共佬"  不用复数  本来就是了
It's "viet cong." there's no "s." it's already plural.
就像你不说中国人人
You wouldn't say "chineses."
够了  这场反抗够了
All right, that's enough of this insubordination!
如果组织散了  我们也就散了
If the machine breaks down, we break down.
嘿  你知道在第一滴血第一部里  他只是个肥猪
Hey, man, you know how in rambo i, he was big but a little puffy
在第一滴血第二部中  就满身肌肉了
And then rambo ii, he got all shredded up?
-对  -你现在就这样
- yeah. - that's kind of how you look right now.
-对  -不是第一部  是第二部
- yeah? - not rambo I but ii.
-真的?  -对当他塑身后
- really? - yeah, when he was cut up.
我倒没有...我是说  那是目标  但现在...
I'm not that... I mean, that's what I'm going for, but you know...
得了  兄弟  你比切条沙拉还有型
Come on, dude. you more shredded than a julienne salad, man.
-谢谢  -秘方是什么
- thanks. - what's the secret, dude?
-饮食  我控制饮食  -真的?
- it's a diet. I'm just dieting. - really?
因为我也想...但太难了
'cause I'm trying to come up a little, but it's just... it's tough.
-你看上去不错  -有小提示么
- you look good. - any tips?
-什么?  -提示  你有么
- what? - any tips, you got?
像比如菠萝
There's, like, the pineapple...
-把地图给我  我日  -嘿
- give me that goddamn map! fuck you! - hey!
-嘿  -好了
- hey! - all right, now!
这是什么  斯奥斯奇  告诉我们的位置
What it is, Sikorski? tell us where we really at.
真他妈鬼扯  这烂招都用
That's fucking bullshit! it's a chump move.
我们只是想听听另外的意见
We just getting a second opinion, doc.
我们走错路了
We're going the wrong way!
-操  -狗娘养的
- damn! - son of a bitch.
天  我认为我们该这样
God! I think we were supposed to be doing this,
但却这样了
And instead we did this.
你觉得能带我们会降落点?
Think you can get us back to that drop zone, boy?
太不爽了
This is not cool!
也许吧
Maybe.
太胡闹了
This is insane!
你们真打算放弃电影?
Are you really going to abandon this movie?
我们本该是个连队
We're supposed to be a unit!
滚他妈的连队
Suck my unit!
好吧  行
All right, fine.
-我自己完成  -你爱咋咋地
- I'll finish it by myself. - you go be all you can be, man.
-塔格  你不知道你要走向何方
Tugg, you have no idea where you're going!
我知道
Yes, I do!
我要  "在黄昏中走到外部雨林"
I'm going to, "exterior, rain forest, dusk.
"独自一人穿过恐惧的丛林  突然转向福尔・立夫"
"smash cut to Four Leaf, who treks alone through a frightening jungle."
去你的连队
Suck on that unit, Kirk!
行了  兄弟们  我们回家
Come on, men. let's get home.
你好螳螂  你很漂亮
Hello, mr. mantis. you're beautiful.
现在如果回想起之前的喧嚣
Now, if you recall that whole hullabaloo
当时好莱坞分为2阵营
Where hollywood was split into schisms,
一些厂牌支持蓝光  另外的支持HD-DVD
Some studios backing blu-ray disc, others backing hd dvd.
人们认为最后是
People thought it would come down to
像素速率和刷新率之争  但其实都一样
Pixel rate or refresh rate, and they're pretty much the same.
真正决定权在游戏和色情的发行上
What it came down to was a combination of gamers and porn.
只要色情电影支持哪种格式
Now, whichever format porno backs
一般就是最后流行的格式
Is usually the one that becomes the most successful.
你知道索尼的PS3配有蓝光光驱
But, you know, sony, every playstation 3 has a blu-ray in it.
你一直在跟我讲话?
You talking to me this whole time?
我在跟听的人讲话
I was talking to whoever was listening to me.
"超级能量"
Booty sweat.
冷  太冷了  真他妈冷
It's cold! it's freezing. I'm fucking cold.
你要我的防弹衣么
You want my flak Jacket?
你疯了么  这么热  像蒸桑拿似的
What, are you insane? it's boiling! it's like a sweat lodge out here!
吵架声音小点
Keep the volume down on that bitching, flatch adams.
我背着12磅的东西呢
I gotta take a fucking 12-pound shit!
-怎样了  情况不错?  -是不错
- how we doing? we making good time? - we're making good time,
但要想在天黑前翻过那座山是不可能的
But there's no way we make it over that ridge before sundown.
好吧  伙计们  我们扎帐篷休息
All right, fellas, we're gonna make camp, rest up!
-天啊  -你们可占便宜了
- oh, god. - y'all might be in for a treat.
当初战争爆发时
You know, back before the war broked out,
我曾在圣安东尼奥服兵役
I was a saucier in san antone.
我打赌能将一些藏匿的人揪出来
I bet I could collar up some of them greens.
就像在稻田里捉小虾一样
Yeah, noodle some crawfish out the paddy, yo.
再弄点酸苹果当甜点  明白吗  当然!
And maybe some crab apples for dessert, now, you hear? hell, yeah!
那就是我们说话的方式  像这样
That's how we all talk. we all talk like this, suh! yes, suh.
是的  在稻田里捉小虾
Yeah, get some crawfish and some ribs.
是澳大利亚人就好好做那里人!  懂吗  "袋鼠杰克"
You're australian! be australian! excuse me, kangaroo Jack.
伙计  我一想到食物就会激动
I get excited about my foods, man.
去死吧!
Die!
不!
No!
伙计  究竟发生什么了?  我们在哪儿?
Dude, dude, what the hell is going on here? where are we?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
我从未出过美国
I've never been outside the states.
什么?  你他妈是在开玩笑吗
Wait, what? are you fucking kidding me?
这一切都他妈是你编造的吗
Did you make this whole goddamn thing up?
伙计  难道你甚至都没参过军?
Dude, were you even in the fucking service?
我当然参过军  不过是海岸巡逻队
Yes. of course. coast guard.
-海岸巡逻队  -公共卫生部门
- coast guard. - sanitation department.
上帝啊  你他妈只是个拣垃圾的!
Oh, my god! you're a fucking garbage man!
妈的  F・L・泰柏克骗了我和整个美国
Damn it. F.L. Tayback lies to me and the whole goddamn u.s. of a.
那本书是对国家的贡献!  我是个爱国者!
I wrote the book as a tribute! I'm a patriot!
好的  就算你有微乎其微的爱国情结
Yeah, you're the milli vanilli of patriots, okay?
你骗了所有人说自己在越南战争上战斗
You lied about fighting the vietnam war.
就像用国旗蒙住世人的脸一样  该死
It's like punching the american flag in the face, god damn it.
上帝啊  我居然还相信了你!
God, and to think I believed in you!
-真不愿和你呆一起  -作家总是在欺骗
- I don't wanna be next to you. - writers lie all the time.
可以把我和别人绑一块吗
Can I be tied to another post? okay.
-瑞克?  -塔格
- Rick? - Tugg.
我杀生了  瑞克
I killed one, Rick.
杀了我世间的最爱
The thing I love most in the world.
维薇卡  挂掉电话  马上!
Vivica, get off the line now!
是个妓女吧  你杀了个妓女
A hooker. all right, you killed a hooker.
冷静  你现在要做的是
Calm down. here's what you're gonna do.
在手上抹一些漂白粉
Get your hands on some bleach,
一些过氧化氢和石灰粉
Some hydrogen peroxide and a shitload of lime.
不  是只熊猫
No, a panda.
我杀了只熊猫
I killed a panda.
阿曼达?  听着  伙计
Amanda? come on, dude.
我是说  那也许都不是她的真名
I mean, that's probably not even her real name.
不  是只熊猫
No, a panda!
一只熊猫?
A panda?
一只可爱的
A sweet, cuddly,
"行为不轨"的小熊猫
Vicious little panda.
上帝啊  塔格!  别那样吓我!
Jesus christ, Tugg! man, don't scare me like that!
这儿很美
It's beautiful here.
你在拍摄点?
You on the set?
我是在这儿
I am the set.
好的  伙计  数码录影机好用吗
All right, man. hey, how's the tivo working out?
别提那玩意了
Screw tivo.
我早就不需要了
I'm way beyond tivo.
上次看过  压根没弄好
Last I checked, they hadn't hooked it up, though.
没有?  没有数码录像机?
Hadn't hooked it up? no tivo?
已经没有关系了
It doesn't matter anymore.
我已经离开了
I've moved on.
你离开去哪?
Where have you moved on to?
另一家经纪公司?
Another agency?
你和谁在一起?
Hey, who is with you?
你还是我的客户  塔格・斯比德曼!  我要拿到数码录像机!
You are still my client, Tugg Speedman! I am getting the tivo!
穿上夹克  我出门了!
Jacket's on, I'm out the door!
塔格?
Tugg?
拜托别炒我鱿鱼
Please don't fire me.
妈妈  好渴啊
Oh, mama. thirsty.
他看起来不好
He doesn't look too good.
我必须喝点什么  才能吐得出来
Must drink, so I can throw something up!
别喝那水!  那水看上去就像细菌培养液
No, no. don't drink that water! that water's like a petri dish!
不要!
No, don't!
阿帕  你还有"超级能量"吗
Alpa, do you have any Booty Sweat?
让他多喝点阿帕的狗屁饮料吧
Yeah, get him chugging on some of Alpa's ass water.
能让他清醒过来的灵丹妙药
That'll bring him around. it's a cure-all.
伙计  你来拍这部片子究竟是为了什么
Man, what you coming out in movies for anyway?
你还需要额外经济来源吗
Did you need another revenue stream?
想要知道我的经济来源吗
For your information, my revenue stream
我每年获利200万美元
Currently generates $2 million a year
均用来作为我公司的慈善捐款
In charitable contributions for my community.
-真够火的  -为什么我会来拍这部电影?
- hot damn. - and why am I in this movie?
也许因为我知道我不得不出演
Maybe I just knew I had to represent,
因为这部电影有一个"黑人"的好角色
Because they had one good part in it for a black man
他们却把角色给了"鳄鱼邓迪"
And they gave it to crocodile dundee.
管好你的嘴  孩子  他可是国宝级人物
Pump your brakes, kid. that man is a national treasure.
我只是想在你的烤肉里加点作料
I just wanted to throw another shrimp on your barbie.
这可不好笑
That shit ain't funny.
伙计们  这又热又臭  我们又累
Hey, fellas! it's hot! we're tired! it stinks!
我只是在和你开玩笑  袋鼠杰克
I'm just fucking with you, kangaroo Jack!
真抱歉一只澳洲犬吃了你的孩子
I'm sorry a dingo ate your baby.
知道真有那回事吗  一位女士失去了孩子
You know that's a true story? lady lost her kid.
-你有点太过分了  -伙计们  冷静点
- you about to cross some fucking lines. - guys, relax and stuff.
你他妈去死吧
You know what? fuck that, man!
我受够了这个澳洲考拉假黑鬼对我说...
I'm sick of this koala-hugging nigger telling me...
四百年来
For 400 years,
那个字眼让我们抬不起头
That word has kept us down.
你他妈说什么呢
What the fuck?
历尽千辛万苦才翻越那座高山
It took a whole lot of trying just to get up that hill.
现在我们迎来了盛大的同盟
Now we up in the big leagues,
终于轮到我们反击了
Getting our turn at bat.
伙计  我们都是一家人
Long as we live, it's you and me, baby.
那是"杰弗逊一家"的主题曲  你真是有问题
That's the theme song for the Jeffersons. you really need help.
是啊  但别看那是主题曲就忽视它的真实性
Yeah. just 'cause it's the theme song, don't make it not true.
让我来告诉你什么才具有真实性
You know what? I'm gonna tell you what's true.
我会指控你的  相信我
I'm gonna tag you back. you better believe that, baby.
伙计们
Guys! hey, guys!
杰夫  离那动物远点
Jeff, stay away from that animal.
我会咬下它的皮  我要...
I'm gonna bite his hide. I need...
撕下它的胃膜当紧身衣
I need to wear his stomach skin like a unitard.
什么也别做!
Ain't nobody doing nothing to no one or body!
如果珀特诺依先生感到有些虚弱  不愿行走
Now, if mr. Portnoy is feeling a little flu-ish, don't wanna walk,
就把他抬到那头偶蹄类动物身上
Put him up on that cloven-hoof animal!
我们还要赶路呢
We got ground to cover!
好的  战俘营  场景67
All right, pow camp, scene 67.
来啊  你们这些混蛋!
Bring it on, Cockburn!
我的身体虽然被俘  精神却仍旧自由
My body may be shackled, but my mind wanders free.
等等  让我再说一遍
Wait, wait, wait, let me do the line again.
再说一遍台词
Let me do the line again.
我的身体虽然被俘  精神却仍旧自由
My body may be shackled, but my mind wanders free.
太好了  再来一遍
Good, again. again.
太好了  现在开始受折磨的场景
Good, good. now let's do the torture scene.
我看见那棵树的两侧都有苔藓
I see moss on both sides of that tree.
也许我不是唯一一个进过训练营的人...
Well, you know, maybe if I wasn't the only one at boot camp...
我肚子真的很疼  伙计们
My belly really hurts, you guys!
不是开玩笑  我想吐
I'm not joking around, I'm nauseous.
让我下来  我要吐了!  我不想像亨德里斯一样死去
Let me off, I gotta puke! I don't wanna die like Hendrix
好的  好的
All right. all right.
杰夫  你没事吧
Are you okay, Jeff?
我好极了
I'm awesome.
不是吧
Holy shit!
大家趴下  趴下
Okay. everyone, down, down, down.
现在我正在感觉自己错了
Man. now I'm tripping.
那像是个战俘营  剧本里提到过
That looks like the pow camp from out the script, yo.
斯比德曼是对的?
Speedman was right?
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
看看那些煮东西的桶  拿枪的守卫
Look at the cooking vats, the armed guards.
像是个海洛因制作工厂
Looks like a heroin processing plant.
当时我们在直升机上坐了几个小时
We were in that chopper for hours.
我甚至感觉我们根本不在越南
I don't even think we're in vietnam anymore.
-妈的  -该死  都不在越南?
- fuck. - shit. we ain't even in 'nam?
是啊  更像是在缅甸或是老挝
No, most likely myanmar or laos.
老挝他妈是什么
What the fuck is laos?
金三角地区
It's the golden triangle.
世界毒品往来聚集地
The world's hard drug superhighway.
你怎么会知道这些
And how do you know about that?
来的路上  我在飞机里的杂志上看见的
It was a really long trip. I read the in-flight magazine.
停拍!
Cut!
你看到什么了?  我这被挡到了
What do you see, man? I'm blocked.
达米安  停拍!
Damien, cut!
Hey, Damien, cut!
他们抓住了斯比德曼
They got Speedman.
看上去情况不妙
And it doesn't look good.
我是川
I am Tran.
你是我工厂的入侵者
You are a trespasser in my poppy fields.
你是毒品管制局的人渣
You are d.e.a. scum!
剧本改写了我没看见吗
Were there some re-writes that I missed?
你想死吗
Do you want to die?
-想吗  -不!
- do you? - no!
拜...托  别...别伤害我!
Please, don't hurt me!
再说一遍
Say that again.
拜托  别伤害我
Please, don't hurt me.
不是!  像之前那样说!
No! like you did before! say it!
快说!
Say it!
拜...托  别...别伤害我!
Please, don't hurt me!
-什么?  -你是笨蛋杰克
- what? - you are simple Jack.
你们看了笨蛋杰克?
You saw simple Jack?
我们很喜欢这个人的故事  笨蛋杰克
We love the tale of this man, simple Jack.
我们这里没什么好东西
We do not have many luxury here.
"笨蛋杰克"是我们唯一拥有的电影
And simple Jack is the only movie we possess.
你们还在看录像机
You got the vhs.
我们看了很多遍
We've watched it many, many times.
你本该得奥斯卡奖的
You should've got oscar.
知道吗  这...
Well, you know. it's...
就算仅仅是被提名...
Just to be nominated...
你受到提名了?
You were nominated?
不  我没有被提名
No, no, no. I wasn't nominated.
我是说就算仅仅是被提名了也好
I'm just saying that to have been nominated would have been nice.
你知道...很商业化...得打广告...
It's just... it's very political. you have to take out ads...
-给我闭嘴  -好的  好的
- shut up now! - okay. okay.
那么  你们打算
So, are you going to
放我走还是...
Let me go, or...
不  我们要拿你换赎金
No. we'll hold you for ransom.
我们会更加富有了
Much more money now!
他正在开会
He's in a meeting.
知道  我只进去和他谈一小会儿
Yeah, I know. in about two seconds with the Pecker.
我会揪下你的乳头
I'm gonna rip your fucking tits off.
想谈谈麻烦事吗  现在有麻烦了
You wanna talk about trouble? that's trouble.
你要干什么  派克
What do you need, Peck?
这句话应该是我问你吧  莱斯
No, more like what do you need, Les?
眼镜?
Glasses?
什么?
What?
让你看清楚"热带惊雷"的合约
So you can read the tropic thunder contract
上面清楚写着  塔格・斯比德曼是我的客户
That guarantees my client, Tugg Speedman,
需要在外景拍摄点安装数字录影机
Some form of digital video recorder on location.
真不敢相信你让他进来了
- huh? - I can't believe you let him in.
听着  混蛋  我现在嫉妒繁忙
Look, fuckstick, I'm incredibly busy,
你马上给我出去
So why don't you get the hell out of her
否则我会把你那家伙揪下来插进你的屁眼
Before I snap your dick off and jam it into your ass?
不  不是说你  海伦
No, not you, helen.
但若你没把效果做好我也会揪下你的乳头
But I will rip your tits off if you don't get me those theaters.
好极了
Perfect.
好啊  伙计  我把扬声器打开
Hey, Tuggernuts, I've got you on speakerphone.
现在我正和莱斯・葛罗斯曼在一起
I'm standing here with Les Grossman,
他现在很想告诉你为什么他要
And he is dying to tell you why he's apparently wiped his ass
拿你数码录影机合约的纸擦屁股了
With the tivo clause from your contract.
我们是火龙帮
We are flaming dragon.
斯比德曼现在在我们手上
Speedman is with us now.
拿5千万来  我们就放他回去
For 50 million, you will get him back.
-能不能把那些...  -你是谁?
- are you gonna get those... - who is this?
-电话怎么会在你手上?  -我们是火龙帮!
- and how did you get this phone? - we are flaming dragon!
笨蛋杰克现在在我们手上
Simple Jack belong to us now.
你说的是真的?
He does, does he?
我来告诉你  笨蛋
Let me tell you something, shitbird.
我从未听过你们那破中介公司
I've never even heard of your little agency.
但如果你认为你能挖的走我的客户...
But if you think you can poach my client...
拿5千万来  否则别想再见笨蛋杰克  我们会杀了他
Send $50 million, or you no see simple Jack again because we kill him.
我是莱斯・葛罗斯曼  你是哪位?
This is Les Grossman. who is this?
我们是火龙帮!
This is flaming dragon!
好吧  火龙帮  去你妈的
Okay. flaming dragon. fuckface.
首先  向后退一大步  操你自己的脸!
First, take a big step back and literally fuck your own face!
我不知道你们要玩什么泛太平洋
Now, I don't know what kind of pan-pacific bullshit power play
集中攻势的鬼把戏  但是亚洲人  杰克是我的人
You're trying to pull here, but asia, Jack, is my territory.
因此无论你怎么想  请再思考一遍
So whatever you're thinking, you better think again.
否则我会去那里
Otherwise, I'm gonna have to head down there,
在那里进行一次残忍的大面积的轰炸
And I will rain down an ungodly fucking firestorm upon you.
那时你他妈就得打电话到联合国
You're gonna have to call the fucking united nations
寻求具有约束力的解决办法
And get a fucking binding resolution
以免被我完全毁了
To keep me from fucking destroying you
我很认真  你们这些王八蛋!
I am talking scorched earth, motherfucker!
我会将你们统统杀光
I will massacre you!
我会干掉你们
I will fuck you up!
-能帮我查出那是谁吗  -好的
- could you find out who that was? go. - yeah. yeah.
戴上这个  更像笨蛋杰克的牙
You wear these. more like simple Jack teeth.
我知道你是我的超级粉丝  那很好...
Hey. look, I know you're a big fan, and that's great...
戴上假牙!
Put teeth in!
快演
Now do movie.
整部电影?
The whole movie?
我不能  我不知道整部电影...
I can't. I don't know the whole...
快演!  不演就杀了你!
You perform! you perform or die!
爸爸
Pa.
更蠢一点!
More stupid!
爸爸  为什么你要让我那么难受呢
Pa, why you gotta make me feel bad?
你们都看见了
You saw what I saw.
若我们袖手旁观  塔格・斯比德曼必死无疑
Tugg Speedman is dead meat if we don't do something soon.
我们得想办法赶紧回到旅馆
Yeah. we could do something by getting our asses back to the hotel,
而那是另一个方向
Which is in the other direction!
那是不对的
Ain't right.
大逃亡中如果史蒂夫・麦奎因和他的伙计们
What would've happened in the great escape
逃跑了  那激烈的场景还怎么上演
If steve mcqueen and them dudes had turned tail and ran?
电影都那么演  他们最后顺利逃走
Well, that's what that movie was about. they were escaping. they ran away.
我同意  但关键是他们都没有袖手旁观
I'm trying to agree with you. the point is they did something.
那我们该怎么做呢
Then what are we supposed to do, huh?
他擦那一支没有子弹的枪  那就是计划吗
'cause he's cleaning a gun with no bullets. yeah, that's a plan.
我就像一个小男孩在紧张的时候玩弄他的小DD
I'm just like a little boy, playing with his dick when he's nervous.
等一下  等一下  等一下
Wait a minute. wait a minute. wait a minute.
我有个主意  这或许有些疯狂
I got an idea. this might be a little crazy.
疯狂也比没有主意强
Crazy's better than nothing.
1998年我为凯迪做过一个低成本的喜剧片
Back in '98, I did a low-budget titty comedy for skinemax.
-性露营  记得吗?  -记得
- sex camp. remember it? - yeah.
总之  我和其他露营者当时必须
Anyway, me and the campers from the uncool camp
冲进有钱女孩的露营地
Had to break into the rich girl camp.
我们做了什么呢
So, what we did,
我们用木桩和内衣做了一个发射机
We built a catapult out of logs and underwear,
我们用这个发射到墙那边然后跳伞着陆
And they shot us over the wall, and we parachuted down.
听着
Look,
-兄弟们  我们已经知道计划了  -好吧
- you guys, we already know the plan. - fine.
我们就按照《热带惊雷》那本书
We do it just like in the book, chapter 26, the wet offensive.
第26章湿漉攻击所写的那样去做
The book of tropic thunder.
是啊  你们读过那本书吗?
Yeah, did you guys read the book?
我看了图片
The flap, I read the back flap and saw the pictures.
没关系  那和剧本是一模一样的
Well, it's okay. it's exactly the same as in the script.
太好了
Cool.
你们都读过剧本的  是吧?
You guys all read the script, right?
我不读剧本  是剧本读我
I don't read the script, script reads me.
那TMD又是什么意思?
What the hell does that even mean?
你到底想到了什么  直接TMD说出来!
What you getting at with the books, scripts? spit that shit out, man!
好吧  湿漉攻击那章
All right. the wet offensive.
奥西里斯和胖子去分散敌人注意来做掩护
Osiris and fats go undercover as a diversion.
莫唐和布鲁克林就渡过河溜进去
Motown and brooklyn sneak in via the river.
是的  但是那些人可是经过训练的士兵
Yeah. but those dudes was trained soldiers.
我们TMD是经过训练的演员
And we trained actors, motherfucker.
是时候像个男人一样行动起来了  我不是说笑的
Time to man up. and I ain't gonna sugarcoat.
我们有人可能甚至会一去不返
Some of us might not even make it back.
你什么意思?  不在同一架飞机上?
What do you mean? like not on the same flight?
阿帕和我已经穿上了土地母亲的自然迷彩服
Alpa and I's already wearing earth mama's natural night camo.
-别激动  本森  -对不起
- cool it, benson. - sorry.
我们要去侦查  大家想个计划  20分钟后回来
We gonna scout, get a plan together. we ain't back in 20, come looking.
我们是火龙帮
We are flaming dragon.
火龙帮是一个海洛因制造商
Flaming dragon's a heroin manufacturer.
亚洲80%的毒品交易都是他们做的
They're responsible for an eighth of the drug trade in asia.
-利润率非常大  -各位!
- huge profit margin. - guys!
可不可以有人告诉我计划是什么?
Would somebody please let me know what the game plan is?
派克!  我们已经控制住情况了
Peck! we have it handled.
请不要打岔  一切都在掌握中
Please, don't interrupt. everything's under control.
知道了  知道了
I got it. got it.
-莱斯・葛罗斯曼  -我们还没拿到钱
- Les Grossman. - we not get money yet.
现在的价钱是10亿!
Price now 100 million!
你们要么现在付钱  否则明天就撕票
You pay now, or tomorrow simple Jack die.
好的  让我记一下
Great. let me get this down.
1亿
100 million.
等等!  我有一个更好的主意
Wait! I got a better idea.
不如不给你1亿
Instead of 100 million,
我们送给你一个芝士JB怎么样
How about I send you a hobo's dick cheese?
然后你杀掉他  该怎么做就怎么做  傻逼
Then you kill him! do your thing! skin the fucking bastard!
放手去做  随你的便
Go to town, man! go to town!
-不...  -在此期间  如往常一样
- no... - in the meantime, and as usual,
去跟你自己搞去吧!
Go fuck yourself!
-不  -我们不和恐怖分子谈判
- no. - we don't negotiate with terrorists.
你疯了吗?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! hey, hey, are you insane?
-我觉得我可以做得更好  -我认为那已经很好了
- I think I could've done that better. - I thought it was good.
他们会杀了他!
They're gonna kill him!
然后我们在媒体上为他悼念
And we'll weep for him, in the press.
以他的名字建一个奖学金
Set up a scholarship in his name.
最后呢  我说的是最终的结果
Eventually, and I'm talking way, way down the road,
我们发一个保险赔偿申请
We file an insurance claim.
最好是在财政年度结束之前
Preferably before the end of the fiscal year.
实际上  保险赔偿的金额比电影损失的还多
Actually, the claim alone would net us more than the movie would lose.
你不是说真的吧
You can't be serious.
我们面对现实吧
Let's face it.
他再也不是什么炙手可热的演员了
The kids aren't dressing up as scorcher for purim anymore.
斯比德曼是个要消失的明星了
Speedman is a dying star,
一个走向黑洞的白人侏儒
A white dwarf heading for a black hole.
那是物理规律  不可避免的
That's physics. it's inevitable.
派克  我们在这里获得了一个绝好的机会
We've been handed an incredible opportunity here, Peck.
宇宙正在和我们交流
The universe is talking to us right now.
你只需要倾听
You just gotta listen.
派克  这就是工作中有趣的地方
See, this is the good part, Pecker. this is when the job gets fun.
要求就会有结果
Ask and you shall receive.
-好啊  -你合作  我们就合作
- all right. - you play ball, we play ball.
我知道你想要糖果
I know you want the goodies.
欢迎来到好糖果屋
Welcome to the goody room.
你有注意听吗?  因为我说的是G5飞机
You paying attention? 'cause I'm talking g5 for the Pecker.
那将是你能享受的
That's how you're gonna roll.
再也不用发传单做宣传
No more frequent flier bitch miles for my boy.
摇摆着穿过你的膝盖!
Swinging past your knees!
或者你也可以良心发现
Or you can grow a conscience
然后看看在下面5分钟里会发生什么
In the next five minutes and see where that takes you.
我明说了吧
Let me get this straight.
你想让我15年的客户
You want me to let my client of 15 years,
我最好的朋友
One of my best friends,
孤独的死在丛林里  为了一点钱和G5飞机?
Die in the jungle, alone, for some money and a g5?
是的
Yes.
一个G5飞机?
A g5 airplane?
是的
Yes.
以及很多钱
And lots of money.
但是妈妈很照顾杰克
But mama take care of Jack a lot.
她什么时候才能醒过来呢?
How many more sleeps before she wakes up again?
对不起  杰克
Sorry, Jack.
她现在在天堂了
She in heaven now.
妈的!  我以为电影就更差劲了
Damn! I thought the movie was bad.
她永远的沉睡了
She sleep forever.
值得赞赏啊  他缓和了弱智的程度
To the man's credit, he's actually eased up on the retard throttle.
现在演出就更平衡  观众能更有共鸣
And now that's added a balance, and the audience can connect.
这是101剧场  但是他还有很长的路要走
I mean, this is theater 101, but, you know, he's had a tough road.
他会成为一个自然主义者
He'll become a naturalist.
-是的  -打破那距离美感
- yeah. - break down the aesthetic distance,
然后...
Then the...
我告诉过你我会打回来的
Told you I'd tag you back.
我可以为我曾经所做的
Can I tell you that I'm sorry
任何攻击行为向你道歉吗
For any offense I might've caused, man?
-我只...  -是一个混蛋?
- I just got caught up in... - in being a dumbass?
我想是的
I guess so.
我不知道为什么你还在做这种婆婆妈妈的事
Why you still doing this chicken george shit, I have no idea.
-我也不知道  -超出我的理解
- neither do i. - it's beyond me.
-超出我的理解  -你困惑了
- it's beyond me. - you confused.
-我确实有点困惑  -我知道
- I am a little confused. - I know.
但是我们和好了吗?
But are we cool?
还没
Not really.
老兄
Hey, man.
-情况怎么样?  -很好  你呢?
- how's it going? - good. yourself?
如果没有关系的话
Hey, so, if it's no big deal,
我想我就在这做后援了吧
I think I'm just gonna hang back here for the mission.
看着东西
Watch the stuff.
-可以吗?  -什么?  不!
- is that cool? - what? no!
我们需要你  杰夫
We need you, Jeff.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
好吧  听着
Okay, look, man.
-我有事要告诉你  -好的
- I got something to tell you. - okay.
你知道我之前吃的那些软糖吗?
You know those jellybeans I was eating?
那些其实不是软糖
Well, they weren't jellybeans, okay?
-那些是毒品  -真的?
- they were drugs. - really?
如果我下去了  靠近那些毒品  我就完了
I get down there near the mother lode, I am done. I'm jonesing bad, man.
我肯定会吸掉那里所有的海洛因
I'm gonna fucking do all the heroin in the fucking world.
如果你们想要我挺过去
If you guys wanna make it through
你们要把我捆在树上
This thing, you gotta strap me to a tree
-你说真的?  -是的  我说真的  一棵树上
- are you serious? - yeah, I'm serious. literally, a tree.
不管怎么样  你们都不要放我走
And you can, no matter what, you can't fucking untie me until it is done,
直到那东西从我身上完全消失
Until it is out of my system.
我会说"老兄  我很好  没问题"
I'm gonna say, "hey, man, I'm cool. it's cool.
"我终于好了  我终于好了  放开我吧"
"i'm finally better. I'm finally better. untie me."
别听我的!  我所说的任何话都是谎言!
Don't listen to me! anything I fucking say is a lie!
明白了
You got it!
再见  妈妈!
Goodbye, mama!
现在你可以在天堂吃冰激淋
Now you can have ice cream in heaven.
我会在睡梦中看到你
I'll see you tonight, when I go to bed, in my head movies.
但是这个梦让我哭泣
But this head movie makes my eyes rain.
被打了一记
Dang. gilligan catching a kidney shot.
-他们把他带走了!  -那真是折磨
- they got him on the move! - that's torture, man.
他们把他关在那里
Okay. that's where they keeping him.
我衣服要裂了
I gotta get cracking on my costume.
你能干针线活吗?
Say, are you good with a needle and thread?
当然
Hell, yeah.
阿帕・奇诺上个春季卖了
Alpa Chino Chinos sold more than five
500万件裤子
Million pairs last spring at the gap
-我自己缝的样式  -我们走
- I sewed them patterns myself, baby. - let's roll out.
这是个树枝小奥斯卡人
It's a little twig man oscar.
我会叫你小胖墩
I'm going to call you half squat.
你可以叫我
And you can call me
爸爸
Papa.
看看这些星星
Wow, look at all those stars.
真的让人感到很渺小
Really makes a guy feel pretty small.
这可能是我们最后一次看星星了
This could be the last time we look at these stars.
那真美
Man, that's beauty.
如今晚的夜色让我思考一切到底是为什么
Nights like tonight make a man wonder what it's all about.
有谁有驱虫喷雾?
Hey, you guys. anybody got some bug spray?
别忽视我!
Don't ignore me!
坚持住  我们会挺过去的
Stick it out, man. we're gonna get through this.
-柯克?  -什么事?
- hey, Kirk? - yeah?
你还在和詹尼弗・拉夫・休伊特约会吗
Are you still dating jennifer love hewitt?
因为我觉得她很辣
'cause I think she's hot.
没有  那只是一些花边绯闻
No, that was just some tabloid conjecture.
兄弟们  我好了  我挺过去了  你们可以给我松绑了
Hey, guys, I'm good. I made it through. you can untie me now.
真好笑
Funny, huh?
在剧团的生活一年中大部分时间都在各地演出
The circus life 280 days a year on location.
很难找到可以接受这个的女孩
It's hard to find a girl that can hang with that, you know?
没一个值得的
Not one worth keeping, nohow.
喂  瑞达?  埃文斯?
Hey, radar? evans?
不  我是凯文
No, it's Kevin.
凯  管他的  过来
Kev, whatever the fuck. come over here.
屁精第三部要开拍了
Fart three is coming down the pike,
如果你过来给我松绑就有一个角色的机会
And there's a role in there for you if you come over and untie me.
杰夫  你得自己挺过去
Jeff, you're just going to have to tough it out.
你妈是个妓女!
Your mother's a cankerous whore!
喂  老兄
Hey, man.
记得刚才我说你妈是个妓女吗?
Remember way back when I said your mother was a cankerous whore?
我很抱歉  我不是那个意思  她不是
I'm sorry, man. I did not mean that. she's not.
你怎么样?
How about you, man?
你也有等待着你的女人吗
You got some little minx waiting for you on the other side of tomorrow?
我吗?
Me?
我甚至都还没有女朋友呢
I've barely even had a girlfriend, and...
我原来倒真想等这个电影放映时能有机会泡妞
I was really hoping I'd get laid when this movie came out,
但那是不可能的了
But that's not gonna happen.
你呢
What about you, masterblaster?
你也有某人等着你回去吗
You got a certain someone you trying to get with back in the states?
什么  阿帕・奇诺吗?  他每天都有10个妞在那等着
What, Alpa Chino? he's like 10 girls deep, 24l7.
不  你没听懂
No. you missing me, man.
我在说很特别的东西
I'm talking about something special. big difference.
说说吧?
How about it?
是的
Yeah.
是的  有的
Yeah, there is.
你们在约会吗?
Well? what's the skinny? y'all been on a date or what?
没有  我是说...
No. I mean...
我一直都想  但是我总是没有勇气去问
I always wanted to, but I guess I just never had the courage to ask.
这...这很复杂
It's... it's complicated.
不  这很简单
No! it's simple as pie, man.
你站好了不要动
You plant your feet in the ground,
你深情的看着她的眼睛  你说
You look her square in the eyes, you say
"宝贝  你和我去约会吧"  就这么简单
"hey, baby, you and me's going on a date." that's the end of story.
-她叫什么名字?  -兰斯
- what's her name? - lance.
"听着  兰斯..."
"listen here, lance..."
兰斯?  你他妈刚才说什么?  兰斯?
Lance? what the fuck did I just hear? lance?
-你刚才说"兰斯"了吗?  -没有!
- did you say "lance"? - no!
-听起来像"兰斯"  -不  我说"南斯"
- that sounded like "lance." - no, I said "nance."
-我说的就是"南斯"  -听起来像"兰斯"
- that's what I said, "nance." - it sounded like "lance."
听着  我是阿帕・奇诺
Look, I'm Alpa Chino, okay?
我喜欢女人!  懂不?
I love the pussy! all right?
过来躺下看星星
Lay your ass back down and look at the stars.
你在写我爱女人的时候
When you wrote I love tha pussy
你是不是正想着在兰斯的额头甩你的蛋蛋?
Was you thinking of dangling your dice on lance's forehead?
不!  什么?  听着
Oh, hell, no! what? come on. look.
-老兄  每个人都曾经是同性恋  -我不是同性恋!
- man, everyone's gay once in a while. - I'm not gay!
这是好莱坞
This hollywood.
我们都集中精神想正经事吧
How about we all get back to work?
-好吧  -这真是荒谬!
- okay. cool. - this is ridiculous!
我们明天还有很重要的事  大家集中精力
We got a big day tomorrow. let's get focused.
阿帕如果你给我松绑  我真的现在就给你口交
Alpa, if you untie me, I will literally suck your dick right now.
我告诉过你最后一次  我喜欢女人!
I told you, for the last time, I love the pussy!
我会抚摸你的蛋蛋
I'll cradle the balls, stroke the shaft,
吞下你的汁液
Work the pipe and swallow the gravy.
过来  老兄  我们做吧
Get it over here, buddy. let's do this.
好的  那么计划是什么?
Okay, so, what's the plan?
你要跟这些人讲越南语吗?
Are you gonna talk vietnamese to those dudes?
不  不  中文普通话
No. no. mandarin chinese.
这是我观察发现他们所说的语言
Which, from what I can tell, is what they speaking down there.
你怎么会知道中文?
How the hell do you know chinese?
和巩俐演的《丝绸和金钱的国家》
Land of silk and money with gong li. second globe, third oscar.
这是我得到第三个奥斯卡和第二个金球奖的电影
Prepped for that one by working in a
我在一个北京纺织工厂做了8个月
Beijing textile factory for eight months
天助我也
That might be our ride.
绳子太紧了
The straps are too tight!
闭嘴跟着我
Shut your mouth and follow my lead.
好的
Okay.
All right.
那里好像是一个放军需物品的小屋
That looks like it could be the munitions hut right there.
我试着到主楼去找斯比德曼
I'm gonna try to find Speedman in the main building.
过来!
Get over here!
-你们在这做什么啊  -他有手
- what are you guys doing here? - he has hands.
-他杀了达米安  -胡扯
- he killed Damien. - bullshit!
-他把杰米・李・柯蒂斯弄瞎了  -差一点
- he blinded Jamie Lee Curtis. - almost!
你们在说什么呀  达米安自己踩地雷上了
What are you talking about? Damien stepped on a old landmine.
这就好  谢天谢地
Sweet. thank god.
-我们得把斯比德曼救出去  -斯比德曼也在这?
- we busting Speedman out. - Speedman's here?
我在这边朝他们开枪
They got my boom boom up here.
你们就照书上写的那样去袭击他们
I take it y'all are doing the wet offensive from the book.
我让你们好好见识一下
I can give y'all a diversion.
我这儿的装备足够把个地方弄的火光冲天
I got enough shit here to light this
恰似骄阳七月的烈焰
Place up like it's the Fourth of fucking july
是的  你的农场
Yes, your farm.
你的农场在哪
Where is your farm,
美国佬?
American?
我的农场?
My farm?
糟糕
Oh, shit.
这他妈的就是老子的农场
Here's my motherfucking farm!
好的  吃枪子儿吧  笨蛋
Yeah! chicka-chickaw, baby!
我是农场主  你他妈的
I'm a lead farmer, motherfucker!
都给我把头低下
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, keep your head down!
都把头低下贴着地面
Keep your head down on the ground!
都不准动  要不老子一枪崩了这小兔崽子
Nobody move or I do the little big guy!
好  现在该开始实施我们的计划了
That's right, we running this program now, j.p.
现在  快点带我找毒品去
Now show me where the drugs are.
你他妈的在搞什么
What the fuck?
这可不是我们的计划
That ain't the plan!
别说我
Don't judge me!
他确实有很严重的问题
He's got a real serious problem.
把你衣服给脱了
Take off your clothes!
快脱
我们现在该怎么办
What do we do now?
原计划进行  找斯比德曼去
Stick with the plan. find Speedman.
阿帕  你在这看着他们不准动  跟我来
Alpa, keep this clown posse down. come on now.
你们都听见了  给我乖乖的  不准动
Y'all heard the man. be suede, don't move!
别TMD动  别动
Fuck your do-rag. fuck your do-rag.
-门!  -1  2  3
- door! - one, two, three!
我去上面  你去下面
I go high, you go low.
趴下  都给我趴下  周润发你他妈的趴下
Get down. get down! get down! chow yun-fat, get the hell down!
你们要再敢抬下头  我就让你们脑袋开花
If I see one more head pop up, it's gonna be bullet whac-a-mole.
快点快点呀
Come on, come on!
-烟雾弹  -现在先别丢
- smoke grenade. - don't drop it now.
给
Here.
-这是什么  -我也不知道叫什么
- what's this? - I don't know what it's called.
我只知道用它时它发出的声音
I just know the sound it makes when it lies.
火柴盒  别动  否则我就开枪了
Don't move, matchbox, or I will shoot you.
我得穿上这个  别动
I'm gonna put on this thing. don't move.
我仍然能看到你
I can still see you.
塔格!
Tugg!
塔格?
Tugg?
终于找到你了
Gotcha.
赶快收拾一下你的东西  我们回家去
Roll your shit up, man. we going home.
回家?
Home?
但是我每天都有5场演出  而且座无虚席
But I'm doing five shows a day for a standing-room-only crowd.
你还不明白么  这里就是我的家
Don't you get it? I already am home.
好吧  朋友  你得明白...
All right, now, dude, you gotta get it...
这个是我儿子给我的
My son gave this to me.
-这是你的树枝朋友?  -他叫树枝娃娃
- that's your stick buddy? - his name is twigman.
他是不是要跟我们走呢
Does he wanna come with us?
你  趴下!
Get the hell down!
你在干什么呢  别动那支枪
What you doing? what you doing? don't touch that gun.
不要  别动那枪
Don't do it! don't touch that gun!
妈的  要是你敢动那抢...
On my momma, if you touch that gun...
-狗屁  开始了  -过来
- oh, shit, it's on! - over here!
掩护我  主角
Shadow me, pinocchio!
烟雾
Smoke!
杰夫  不要
Jeff, don't!
我做什么都无所谓了
It doesn't matter what I do.
我就是个扫把星总把事情搞砸  没人会尊敬我
I'll always be a screw-up. no one'll ever respect me.
不是的  你可不是扫把星  你能带给我们欢笑
That is not true, you are not a screw-up! you make so many people laugh.
他们只是笑我放屁
They only laugh at my farts.
杰夫  我们现在真的该走了
Jeff, we really need to go now!
我是罪有应得!
This is all I deserve!
敢笑话我  你们这群杂种!
Laugh at that, you bastards!
很可笑  很滑稽啊
Hilarious! hilarious!
我们走吧  再过16小时他们就醒来了
Let's move. we only have 16 hours before they wake up.
听起来像是要吃晚饭的铃声
Sounds like the dinner bell's ringing.
这群混账看来是要爬进来生吞了我们
These assholes are gonna be crawling in here ready to fucking eat us.
这  好了  你就在这呆着
There. all right, you keep six right here.
快点  我们走
Come on, let's go.
快呀  你们磨蹭什么啊  我们得快点了
Come on, what are you guys doing? let's get out of here!
他现在失去自我了
He's on tilt status.
我扮演内尔・阿姆斯特朗在月球探测器时也这样过
Same thing happened to me when I played Neil Armstrong in moonshot.
后来他们在伯班克的一条小道上发现的我
They found me in an alley in Burbank
还在一个旧冰箱盒里想要重新融入地球
Trying to re-enter the earth's atmosphere in an old refrigerator box.
给我喷火器  你得去开直升机
Give me the flame thrower. you gotta start the chopper.
-不  不给  给我  -没时间了  我会处理好的
- no, fuck that! just give me this. - no time! I'll take care of this!
好吧  把你的钩子给我
All right. give me your hooks.
别担心  我反正也不会再用了
Don't worry, I'm not gonna put them on again.
-快点给我  -好  给
- just give me your goddamn hooks. - all right. here.
把那帮兄弟带上直升机  要快啊
Get those boys back to the bird, pronto!
妈的  还没玩够啊
Shit! enough!
破烂假货
Fake shit!
他妈的
Fuck!
快去找你的同伴们  把他们带到直升机那
Go get your guys! get them to the chopper!
我来对付这群混蛋
I'll take care of these yahoos!
你给我好好听着  然后跟我说
You're gonna focus up now, motherfucker, and say it.
-是我  塔格  -是我  塔格
- "it's me, Tugg!" - it's me, Tugg.
很好  现在告诉我  塔格是谁
That's right! now, Tugg who?
-塔格什么  我?  -我不知道  你是谁
- Tugg who? I don't know. who are you? - me?
我知道我是谁
I know who I am!
我是在电影里演那个假扮另一个家伙的家伙
I'm a dude playing a dude disguised as another dude.
什么
What?
你却是一个都不知道自己谁的家伙
You a dude that don't know what dude he is!
还是你是一个不知道自己是谁的家伙
Or are you a dude who has no idea what dude he is
却假装知道自己是谁...
And claims to know what dude he is...
你们到底在说些什么呀
What the fuck are you guys talking about?
...假扮另一个家伙?
...by playing other dudes?
我知道我是谁
I know what dude I am!
-你害怕了  -我才没害怕  我怕什么
- you're scared. - I ain't scared. scared of what?
或者是怕谁
Or scared of who?
-怕谁  -快点吧  我们真得快点离开了
- scared of who? - come on, guys. we really need to go!
怕你自己
Scared of you.
-俄滴娘啊  -这到底是怎么了
- jesus. - what's going on?
家伙要浮现出来了
The dudes are emerging.
他是对的
He's right, you know.
我不是
I am not
林肯・奥西里斯上士
Sergeant Lincoln Osiris.
我们得快点走了
We gotta roll out.
我也不是奥玛来爸爸
Nor am I father O'malley.
或者是内尔・阿姆斯特朗
Or Neil Armstrong.
我想...我只是一个无名小卒
I think I might be nobody.
你们俩内心的不安全感也太荒谬了吧
The insecurity level with you guys is ridiculous!
-"家家"有本难念的经  -是的  都有过
- everybody's got issues! - yeah, man, everybody got issues.
你是柯克・拉扎勒斯
Come on! you're Kirk Lazarus.
就是因为你  我才喜欢上演戏的
You're the whole reason I got into acting.
我在戏剧学院的时候能背出
I memorized every single monologue
你所演的每一部剧的每一句台词
You ever did when I was in theater school.
-不会吧  -是的  听着  塔格
- really? - yeah. and look, Tugg!
我在8年级的时候  看了24遍炙热人物Ⅰ
I saw scorcher I 24 times when I was in eighth grade.
那影片让我神魂颠倒  我喜欢死了  你是纯爷们
That shit blew me away! I got high to that shit! you the man!
是的  炙热人物Ⅰ太棒了  我们快走吧
Yeah, man, scorcher I was great. let's get the fuck out of here!
塔格  现在只剩下你了  朋友
Tugg, Tugger, you're the last piece of the puzzle, buddy.
我们需要你  你的朋友需要你  跟我们走吗
We need you! your men need you! are you with us?
我是幻想雄鸡
I'm a rooster illusion.
妈的  我们以后再跟他讲道理
Fuck it. we'll deal with him later.
我们快走吧  快  加速  走
Let's move. come on. come on. double time. gotta go!
好的  开始行动
Bingo! move out.
尝尝这个  你个嗑药的侏儒
Just say no to this, you drug-making midget.
坚持住
Gotta hold on!
福尔・立夫
Four Leaf!
你长出手来了?
You grew hands?
火箭筒  同志们
Rpg, gentlemen!
你们干吗
Where are you going?
做完这个我要转行到饮食业
Oh, my god. I am moving to catering after this.
我的屁股
My ass!
我们得振作起来  塔格
Hey, yo! we gotta get our shit together, Tugg!
我们得把他弄到直升机那
We gotta get his cracker ass to the chopper!
你还疯着吗  我们得把坎斯基弄到直升机那
Are you still crazy? we gotta get candisky to the chopper!
是斯基
It's Sandusky.
-凯文・斯基  -是我
- Kevin Sandusky. - that's my name.
你记得我名字
You remembered my name.
阿帕  你去帮一下科迪
Alpa, go help Cody.
珀特诺依把斯基带到直升机那  快
Portnoy, get Sandusky back to the chopper. go!
-好  他就交给我了  -我们走吧
- I got him! - let's go!
我们得快点离开这了
Let's get out of here!
立夫
Hey, Leaf!
-立夫  -干什么
- Leaf! - yeah.
我们的人一过了桥
Hit the plunger
你就按下活塞  -好的
- as soon as they clear the bridge! - got it!
快  上飞机
Come on! get in the chopper!
-快  -柯克  等一下
- come on! move! - Kirk! wait!
-他究竟在做什么  -拉兹我要炸掉整个桥了
- what the hell is he doing? - Laz, I'm gonna blow the bridge!
立夫要炸掉整个桥了  快点啊
Leaf's about to blow the bridge. come on!
你不用这样  真的不用  我得留下来
You don't have to! you don't have to! I'm staying.
不  我不能让你这样做  伙计  我们得走了
No, I can't let you do that, mate. we gotta go.
不  说真的  我现在不疯了
No, I'm telling you, I'm not being crazy. they'll listen to me.
我知道这听起来很怪异  但是我和他们有感情了
I know it sounds weird, but I have a connection with them.
-快过来啊  -我现在有孩子了 是一个小胖墩
- get over here! - I have a son now. little half squat.
哎呀  什么小胖墩啊  谁啊
Who in crikey fuck is half squat?
他是我儿子  我儿子
He's my son. he's my boy!
他需要我  我得回到他身边
He needs me. I have to go back to him.
你出去后  告诉世人这里发生的事情
You tell the world what happened here.
这发生什么了
What happened here?
我不知道  但是你得告诉他们
I don't know, but you need to tell them.
我没事了
I got this.
塔格!
Tugg!
照顾好兄弟们  我来处理这些人
You take care of the boys! I'll deal with these guys.
他要去哪  我们都要死了!
Where is he going? we're gonna fucking die!
拉兹  快走  他可以加入那个马戏团了
Laz, come on. he joined the circus. let's go.
-你有手了  -是的
- you've got hands. - yeah.
-你有手了  -快点
- fuck! you've got hands? - come on!
-快点  -进来
- come on! - get in!
-快  -他要呆在这?
- come on! - he's staying?
走吧  别再和他白费精力了  快离开这
Go! he's a lost cause, mate! get out of here!
我错了  炸掉这桥  快炸掉这桥
I was wrong! blow the bridge! blow the fucking bridge!
我来搞定
I got this.
立夫  不要
Leaf, no!
完了  他挂了
It's over! he's gone!
科迪  我们得走了
Cody! we gotta go!
看呐
Look.
我想他不行了
Think he's done.
掩护我
Cover me!
-快  -等一下  回来
- come on! - wait, come back!
我们怎么掩护他呀
How do we cover him?
好吧  游戏结束了  快起来  伙计
All right, game over. come on, mate. come on.
-你还好吗  -我好冷
- you all right, man? - I'm cold.
我感觉不到我的腿了
I can't feel my legs.
不不  它们在泥坑里呢  看  在泥坑里
No, no, they're in a puddle, mate. see? there's a puddle right there.
-别担心  -好
- no worries. - good.
快  我们得走了
Come on, we gotta split, man.
-你们为我而回来了  -当然
- you guys came back for me. - course.
我想要你知道...
Hey! I want you to know something.
什么
What?
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是我的朋友...
You're my friend.
我的好兄弟
You're my brother.
真的  知道么  你是个很酷的兄弟
But like a really cool brother, you know?
没有仇恨  没有...
Like a brother where there was no animosity or...
看呐  你真的哭出眼泪来了
Don't look now, you got some real tears going.
真的吗
Really?
这是感动的泪水
That's the stuff that accolades are made of.
天呐  你们在搞什么  快走哇
Jesus, let's go, man!
快  快  快走啊
Come on! come on! come on! let's go! let's go!
进去  进去
Get in! get in!
快  好  我们出发
Come on! here we go!
笨蛋塔格  我搞到了
Tuggernuts! I got it!
-塔格!  -瑞克!
- Tugger! - Rick!
什么情况?
What the fuck?
我搞到数码录像机了
I got the tivo!
我绝对是有求必应
My friend wants a tivo, my friend gets a tivo!
这届的奥斯卡奖获得者是...
And the oscar goes to...
好极了  塔格・斯比德曼
Yes! Tugg Speedman.
"热带大失策  一个投资最大的假战争片"
"tropic blunder, the true story behind the making
"背后的真实故事"
"of the most expensive fake true war story ever."
很好  你这狗娘养的
Yeah, you son of a bitch!
8项大奖  4亿美元
Eight oscars, $400 million
是你拯救了塔格・斯比德曼的事业
And you saved Tugg Speedman's career.
没有你  我也做不到  斯洛姆
I couldn't have done it without you, slolom.
是吗
Really?
不  白痴  我当然可以
No, dickhead, of course I could.
-连猴子都能做你的工作  -那我...
- a nutless monkey could do your job. - well, i...
现在  喝上几杯  然后接受所有的荣誉...
Now, go get drunk and take credit at all the parties.
-我永远不会这样子对...  -开玩笑的
- I would never do that to... - joking.
-是吗  -是的
- yeah? - yeah.
很...好  真有你的
Very... okay, there he is.
-真有你的  好吧  -玩开心
- there he is. okay. - go have fun.
好的  我们会...
All right. we're having a...
谢谢  莱斯  也祝你晚上那个愉快
Fuck, okay. thank you, Les. thank you. you have a good night...
但是说真的  猴子都能做你的工作
But seriously, a nutless monkey could do your job.
好的  谢谢你  先生
Good. thank you, sir.